<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cv>
"CURRICULUM VITAE  <label type="Name">Elodia Hal Considine</label>  University of Missouri  School of Social Work  703 Clark Hall  Columbia, Missouri 65211  (123)345-7890  fitchd@missouri.edu    EDUCATION  2001    Ph.D., School of Social Work, University of Texas at Arlington  Dissertation title: A Description of the Child Protective Services Investigative Decision Making  Context with Implications for Decision Support System Design  Dissertation Chair: Richard Schoech    1984    M.S.S.W., School of Social Work, University of Texas at Arlington  Thesis title: The Relationship of Religious Fundamentalism with Ego Development and a  Progressive Community Attitude  Thesis Chair: Charles Mindel    1981    B.A. Religion, Oklahoma Baptist University    ACADEMIC AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE  2015  Present Associate Professor, School of Social Work, University of Missouri  2009  2015  Assistant Professor, School of Social Work, University of Missouri  2010  2015  Affiliate, Center for Violence and Injury Prevention, George Warren Brown  School of Social Work, Washington University  2001  2009  Assistant Professor, School of Social Work, University of Michigan  1999  2000  Adjunct Professor, School of Social Work, University of Texas at Arlington  1992  1998  Field Instructor, School of Social Work, University of Missouri  1998  1999  Social Services Coordinator/Data Analyst, Harris Methodist Hospital, Fort  Worth, Texas  1991  1998  Medical Social Worker, Associate Director, Child Protection Program,  University of Missouri Hospital &amp; Clinics  1990  1998  Therapist, Mid-Missouri Mental Health Center, Columbia, Missouri  1989  1990  Medical Social Worker, Childrens Hospital of Oklahoma, Oklahoma City,  Oklahoma  1989  1990  Therapist, Parents Assistance Center, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma  1986  1989  Therapist, Lode Star Center, Moore, Oklahoma  1985  1989  Therapist, Central Oklahoma Juvenile Treatment Center, Tecumseh, Oklahoma  1984  1985  Caseworker, Salvation Army, Fort Worth, Texas    FELLOWSHIPS &amp; AWARDS  Presidents (MU System) Award for Intercampus Collaboration, 2015  SAGE/CSWE Award for Innovative Teaching in Social Work Education, 2013  Provost Outstanding Junior Faculty Teaching Award, 2012  Outstanding Faculty Award, School of Social Work Alumni Organization, 2011  Phi Alpha Student Honor Society, Honorary Faculty Member, 2011  Difficult Dialogues Fellow, University of Michigan, Ford Foundation Initiative, 2006  2007  Distinguished Service, Prevent Child Abuse Missouri, 1995  1998  Omicron Delta Kappa, 1981    SCHOLARLY/RESEARCH SUPPORT  Under Review  Asthma Empowerment - Kansas City. National Institutes of Health - National Heart, Lung, and  Blood Institute, $6,852,988 (six years), co-I.  Active  Online Master of Social Work Program. University of Missouri, Mizzou Online. Awarded $250,000  (two years), PI (2016  2018).  Not Funded  Exploring Predictors of Divergent Legal Outcomes: Abusive Head Trauma as a Case Study. National  Science Foundation, Law &amp; Social Sciences, $521,792 (two years), PI, 2015.  Child &amp; Elder Abuse Indexing Algorithm for an Information Retrieval System. National Science  Foundation, Information and Intelligent Systems, $119,821 (two years), PI, 2015.  Worldview of Cyber\xe2\x80\x90Physical Security and Privacy. European Union  Horizon 2020, $234,000 (two  years), co-PI, 2014.  Collaborative Research: Reliability Modeling for Cyber-Physical Infrastructures. (2013) National  Science Foundation, CPS-Synergy, $188,747 (three years), co-PI.  The Interaction Dependence of Policy Making and Research Processes on the Use of Research Evidence in  Children Services. (2014) William T. Grant Foundation, $392,305 (two years), PI.  Completed  Online Master of Social Work Program. University of Missouri, Mizzou Online. Awarded $200,314  (two years), PI (2014  2015).  Title IV-E MSW Child Welfare Training Program. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.  Awarded $729,000 (per year), co-PI (2010  2013).    DALE K. FITCH - Page 2 of 15    Child &amp; Elder Abuse Thesaurus for an Information Retrieval System. University of Missouri Research  Board. Awarded $33,137, co-PI. Project period: March 2012  August 2013.  Court Improvement Data Grant Project. Michigan Supreme Court. Awarded $41,300, PI. Project  period: January 2008  December 2008.  Design for a Virtual Workforce Database Management System. The Guidance Center's Center for  Excellence. Awarded $22,936, PI. Project period: July 2007  December 2007.  A Study of Social Workers Genetic Beliefs. University of Michigan Office of the Provost. Awarded  $14,781, co-PI. Project period: June 2005  May 2007.  The Use of ePortfolios and XML in Evaluating Curriculum and Student Learning. ITCommons  Emergent Project Award. Awarded $8,688, PI. Project period: February 2005  December 2005.  Evaluating Portfolio Approaches for the School of Social Work. University of Michigan Office of the  Provost. Awarded $10,000, PI. Project period: February 2004  August 2005.  Legal Outcomes for Abusive Head Trauma Cases. University of Michigan Office of the Vice  President for Research. Awarded $10,000, PI. Project period: July 2003  June 2005.  Head Start Family Information System - Phase II. Kellogg Foundation Global Program on Youth.  Awarded $23,948, PI. Project period: May 2003  April 2004.    PEER REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS  Fitch, D., Canada, K., Cary, S., &amp; Freese, R. (2016). Facilitating social work role plays in online  courses: The use of video conferencing. Advances in Social Work, 17(1), 78  92. doi:  10.18123/456789  Patton, D. Sanchez, N., Fitch, D., Macbeth, J., &amp; Leonard, P. (2015). I know Gods got a day 4 me:  Violence, trauma, and coping among gang-involved Twitter users. Social Science Computer  Review. doi: 10.1123/3454789015613319  Fitch, D. (2015). A conceptual framework for information technology in social work practice.  Advances in Social Work, 16(1), 15  30.  Fitch, D., Watt, J.W., &amp; Parker-Barua, L. (2014). Envisioning public child welfare agencies as  learning organizations: Applying Beers Viable System Model to Title IV-E program evaluation.  Journal of Public Child Welfare, 8(2), 119-142. doi: 10.1123/34547890.2123.456789  Quinn, A., &amp; Fitch, D. (2014). A conceptual framework for contextualizing information  technology competencies. Journal of Technology in Human Services, 32(1-2), 133-148.  doi:10.1123/34527890.2123.456789  DALE K. FITCH - Page 3 of 15    Fitch, D. (2014). An organizational cybernetics framework for achieving balance in  evidence-based practice and practice-based evidence. Journal of Evidence-Based Social Work, 11(12), 114  126. doi: 10.1123/34537890.2123.456789  Fitch, D., Benner, K. Cary, S., &amp; Freelin, T. (2013). ePortfolios in social work curriculum:  Demonstrating integrative and reflective learning. The Journal of Baccalaureate Social Work, 18(S1),  113 - 124.  Fitch, D., Sedigh, S., Mcmillin, B, &amp; Akella. R. (2013). CPS-CSH cyber-physical analysis and  design. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 7722, 92-105. doi: 10.1007/978-3-123-456789-5_9  Fitch, D., &amp; Jagolino, N. (2012). Examining organizational functioning through the lens of  complexity theory using system dynamics modeling. Journal of Social Service Research, 38(5), 591604. doi:10.1123/34587890.2123.456789  Fitch, D. (2012). Youth in foster care and social media: A framework for developing privacy  guidelines. Journal of Technology in Human Services, 30(2), 94  108. doi:  10.1123/34527890.2123.456789  Fitch, D., Kaiser, M., &amp; Parker-Barua, L. (2012). Student, curricular and public agency needs: A  focus on competency achievement. Systemic Practice and Action Research, 25(5), 417  439. doi:  10.1007/s11123-345-7890-1  Fitch, D., &amp; Grogan-Kaylor, A. (2012). Using agency data for evidence-based programming: A  university-agency collaboration. Evaluation and Program Planning, 35(1), 105-112. doi:  10.1016/j.evalprogplan.2011.08.004  Quinn, A., Fitch, D., &amp; Youn, E. (2011). Considering construct validity in distance educational  research in social work education. Journal of Social Work Education, 47(2), 321-336.  Fitch, D. (2010). Homeless management information system customization intervention. Journal  of Human Behavior in the Social Environment, 20(2), 255-271.  Fitch, D. (2009). A shared point of access to facilitate interagency collaboration. Administration in  Social Work, 33(2), 186-201.  Fitch, D., Peet, M., Reed, B.G., &amp; Tolman, R. (2008). The use of ePortfolios in evaluating the  curriculum and student learning. Journal of Social Work Education, 44(3), 37-54.  Fitch, D., Gibbs, T., Peet, M., Reed, B.G., &amp; Tolman, R. (2007). XML and ePortfolios. Journal of  Educational Technology Systems, 36(3), 319-333.    DALE K. FITCH - Page 4 of 15    Fitch, D. (2007). Balancing evidence-based practice with practice-based evidence: A cybernetic  framework. International Multi-Conference on Society, Cybernetics and Informatics, Orlando,  Florida, vol. 2, 254-258.  Fitch, D. (2007). Wherefore wikis? Journal of Technology in Human Services, 25(4), 79-85.  Fitch, D, &amp; Shaffer, J. (2007). An alternative database table design. Journal of Technology in Human  Services, 25(3), 57-79.  Fitch, D. (2007). Designing databases around decision making. In M. Cortes &amp; K. Rafter (Eds.),  Nonprofits and Technology: Emerging Research for Usable Knowledge (pp 135  147). Chicago, IL:  Lyceum.  Fitch, D. (2007). Structural equation modeling the use of a risk assessment instrument in child  protective services. Decision Support Systems, 42(4), 2137-2152.  Fitch, D. (2006). A cybernetic evaluation of organizational information systems. In B. Williams &amp;  I. Iman (Eds.), Systems Concepts in Evaluation: An Expert Anthology (pp 61-74). Point Reyes, CA:  EdgePress of Inverness.  Fitch, D. (2006). Examination of the child protective services decision-making context with  implications for decision support system design. Journal of Social Service Research, 32(4), 117-134.  Fitch, D. (2005). General system theory and the child abuse investigation decision making  context. Journal of Applied Systems Studies, 6(2).  Spencer, M., Fitch, D., Grogan-Kaylor, A., &amp; McBeath, B. (2005). The equivalence of the behavior  problem index across U.S. ethnic groups. Journal of Cross-Cultural Psychology, 36(5), 573-589.  Fitch, D. (2005). Diffusion of technology in the human services. Journal of Teaching in Social Work,  25(1/2), 191-204.  Fitch, D. (2004). Client-controlled case information: A general system theory perspective. Social  Work, 49(3), 497-505.  Schoech, D., Fitch, D., MacFadden, R., &amp; Schkade, L. (2001). From data to intelligence:  Introducing the intelligent organization. Administration in Social Work, 26(1), 1-22.    MANUSCRIPTS UNDER REVIEW, REVISION, OR IN PREPARATION  Fitch, D., Griffin, J., Rydahl, T., Gray, A., Willis, B., &amp; Skubic, M. (Under review). Gender  specific exergame design considerations. Games for Health.    DALE K. FITCH - Page 5 of 15    Sage, M., Fitch, D., &amp; Quinn, A. Use of social media in direct practice: An examination of  ethical use frameworks. In preparation. Social Work.  Fitch, D., Yoo, I., &amp; Mosa, A. Child and elder abuse thesaurus for an information retrieval  system. In preparation. Research on Social Work Practice.    INVITED PUBLICATIONS  Fitch, D. \xe2\x80\x9cRedefining Education.\xe2\x80\x9d The Innovator, Fall 2013, 12(2).  Fitch, D. \xe2\x80\x9cControlling Their Story: Protecting the Privacy of Foster Care Youth.\xe2\x80\x9d CW360\xc2\xb0. Spring  2011, pp. 7, 13-14.    JOURNAL BOOK REVIEWS    Fitch, D. (2007). [Review of the Book \xe2\x80\x9cInformation Technology for Social Work: Practice Skills  for the 21st Century\xe2\x80\x9d]. Administration in Social Work, 31(4), 125-127.  Fitch, D. (2010). [Review of the Book \xe2\x80\x9cQualitative Research Design for Software Users\xe2\x80\x9d].  Qualitative Social Work, 9(2), 287-291,    PUBLISHER BOOK REVIEWS  Sidell, N. (2014). Social Work Documentation Skills: A Guide to Strengthening Your Case Recording,  Second Edition. Washington, DC: NASW Press.  Dudley, J. (2013). Research Methods for Social Work: Being Producers and Consumers of Research  (Updated Edition). New York, NY: Pearson.  Frasier, L., Rauth-Farley, K., Alexander, R., &amp; Parrish, R. (2006). Abusive Head Trauma in Infants  and Children: A Medical, Legal, and Forensic Reference. St. Louis: G.W. Medical Publishing.  Brueggemann, W. (2006). The Practice of Macro Social Work (3rd ed.) Belmont, CA : Thomson  Higher Education.  Schiller, P. (2005). Information Technology for Social Work: Practice Skills for the 21st Century.  Boston: Pearson, Allyn and Bacon.    TECHNICAL REPORTS  Fitch, D. (2012). Critical systems heuristics on youth in care and social media. KVC Behavioral  Healthcare, Inc., Olathe, KS.  Fitch, D. (2007, 2008). CAFAS report. Vista Maria Residential Treatment Center, Dearborn  Heights, MI.    DALE K. FITCH - Page 6 of 15    Fitch, D. (2007). Demonstrating the Michigan difference: Status overview of ePortfolio pilot sites &amp;  support from campus leaders. Associate Provost for Academic, Information and Instructional  Technology Affairs, University of Michigan.  Fitch, D. (2006). ePortfolio project: IT partnership year-end report. Director of IT Campus Initiatives  &amp; CARAT, University of Michigan.  Ortiz, L., Hernandez, S., Fitch, D., Francis, E., &amp; Aranda, A. (2005). Latinos in social work  education: Demographics and strategies for change. Cited in \xe2\x80\x9cToolkit on Recruitment &amp; Retention of  Historically Underrepresented Faculty and Doctoral Students in Social Work Education,\xe2\x80\x9d  www.cswe.org  Hern\xc3\xa1ndez, S. H., &amp; Fitch, D. (2004). Ideological dislocation: Implications for mentoring Latino  social work faculty. Cited in \xe2\x80\x9cToolkit on Recruitment &amp; Retention of Historically  Underrepresented Faculty and Doctoral Students in Social Work Education,\xe2\x80\x9d www.cswe.org    REPRESENTATIVE CONFERENCE PAPERS AND PRESENTATIONS  Fitch, D., &amp; Kaplan, M. (2016, April). How to use web videoconferencing to teach social work practice  skills. Refereed paper presented at the Social Work Distance Education Conference,  Indianapolis, IN.  Fitch, D. (2016, January). Engagement in asynchronous online learning. Invited presentation at the  Teaching Renewal Week, University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.  Jacobs-Kenner, J., &amp; Fitch, D. (2015, November). Ethical use of social media to support positive  practice and promote human service organizations. Invited paper presented at the Missouri  Coalition of Children's Agencies Annual Meeting, Osage Beach, MO.  Fitch, D., &amp; Canada, K. (2015, October). Evaluating online video conferencing platforms to conduct  social work role plays. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council  on Social Work Education, Denver, CO.  Sage, M., Quinn, A., Fitch, D., &amp; Young, J. (2015, October). Engaging students in an online learning  environment. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social  Work Education, Denver, CO.  Fitch, D., Canada, K., Freese, R., &amp; Cary, S. (2015, April). Use of online video conferencing to  facilitate social work role plays. Refereed paper presented at the Social Work Distance Education    Conference, Indianapolis, IN.  Fitch, D. (2015, January). Social work professionals use of social media with youth in care. Refereed  paper presented at the Society for Social Work Research, New Orleans, LA.    DALE K. FITCH - Page 7 of 15    Quinn, A., Fitch, D., Young, J., &amp; Sage, M. (2014, October). Engaging students in an online learning  environment. Invited panel presentation at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social  Work Education, Tampa, FL.  Fitch, D. (2014, January). An empirical exploration of organizational cybernetics in three  human service agencies. Refereed paper presented at the Society for Social Work Research, San  Antonio, TX.  Fitch, D. (2013, November). Mobile device facilitated community development network. Invited panel  presentation at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social Work Education, Dallas,  TX.  Fitch, D. (2013, November). ePortfolios as a concurrent process to facilitate integrative and reflective  learning. Invited paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social  Work Education, Dallas, TX.  Fitch, D., Yoo, I., &amp; Mosa, A. (2013, November). Child and elder abuse thesaurus for an information  retrieval system. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on  Social Work Education, Dallas, TX.  Sage, M., Quinn, A., &amp; Fitch, D. (2013, November). Use of social media in direct practice:  Implications for training and policy. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of  the Council on Social Work Education, Dallas, TX.  Fitch, D. (2012, November). Friending your clients on Facebook: How social media influences child  welfare practice. Invited presentation for the US Department of Health &amp; Human Services,  Administration for Children &amp; Families, Children's Bureau Centennial Webinar. 339 attendees.  Quinn, A., Fitch, D., &amp; Cary, S. (2012, November). An examination of how field agencies view  information technology competencies. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of  the Council on Social Work Education, Washington, DC.  Fitch, D., &amp; Kaiser, M. (2011, October). An empirical investigation of employee engagement in a public  child welfare agency. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on  Social Work Education, Atlanta, GA.  Fitch, D., Watt, J.W., &amp; Parker-Barua, L. (2011, October). A public child welfare agency as a learning  organization. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social  Work Education, Atlanta, GA.  Fitch, D. (2011, April). Child welfare meets technology and social media: Help or hindrance? Invited  presentation presented at the Center for Advanced Studies in Child Welfare Conference on    DALE K. FITCH - Page 8 of 15    Social Media, Smartphones, and Safety: How Technology is Changing Child Welfare Practice,  Minneapolis, MN.  Fitch, D., Kaiser, M., &amp; Parker-Barua, L. (2010, October). Meeting state expectations and curricular  needs by focusing on competency achievement. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program  Meeting of the Council on Social Work Education, Portland, OR.  Quinn, A., Fitch, D., &amp; Flanagan, K. (2010, October). Practice informs research: An examination of  how field agencies view research. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the  Council on Social Work Education, Portland, OR.  Quinn, A., Fitch, D., &amp; Youn, E. (2009, November). Discussing construct validity of on-line  education research for the purpose of generalization. Refereed paper presented at the Annual  Program Meeting of the Council on Social Work Education, San Antonio, TX.  Fitch, D., &amp; Reed, B.G. (2008, May). Automated curricular assessment using qualitative data.  Refereed paper presented at the Fourth International Congress of Qualitative Inquiry,  University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.  Fitch, D. (2007, October). An electronic referral system to facilitate interagency case coordination.  Refereed paper presentation presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social  Work Education, San Francisco, CA.  Alvarez, A., &amp; Fitch, D. (2007, October). Integrative learning and portfolio development for socially  just practice. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social  Work Education, San Francisco, CA.  Ortega, R., Voshel, E., Fitch, D., &amp; Alvarez, A. (2007, October). Promoting socially just practice in  the field of social work: Lessons learned. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting  of the Council on Social Work Education, San Francisco, CA.  Fitch, D. (2007, August). Methodological considerations integrating disparate human services  information systems. Refereed paper presented at the 8th International Conference of Human  Services Information Technology Applications, Toronto, CA.  Fitch, D. (2007, July). Balancing evidence-based practice with practice-based evidence: A cybernetic  framework. Refereed paper presented at the 3rd International Conference on Social and  Organizational Informatics and Cybernetics, Orlando, FL.  Fitch, D. (2007, May). I&amp;R centers and wikis: The best of both technologies. Refereed paper presented  at the 29th I&amp;R Annual Training and Education Conference of the Alliance of Information and  Referral Systems, Jacksonville, FL.    DALE K. FITCH - Page 9 of 15    Fitch, D. (2006, September). A shared point of access to facilitate interagency collaboration. Refereed  paper presented at the 35th Annual Conference of the Association for Research on Nonprofit  Organizations and Voluntary Action, Chicago, IL.  Fitch, D. (2006, September). Realizing benefits of participating in HMIS for consumers and case  managers. Invited paper presented at the 2006 National Homeless Management Information  System Conference, Denver, CO.  Fitch, D. (2006, February). Emancipatory principles in human services information systems design.  Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social Work  Education, Chicago, IL.  Fitch, D., Peet, M., Reed, B., &amp; Tolman, R. (2006, February). The use of ePortfolios in assessing social  justice practice competencies development. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program  Meeting of the Council on Social Work Education, Chicago, IL.  Fitch, D., Peet, M., Reed, B., &amp; Tolman, R. (2005, February). The use of XML in evaluating  curriculum and student learning. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the  Council on Social Work Education, New York City, NY.  Fitch, D., Peet, M., Reed, B., &amp; Tolman, R. (2005, February). The use of ePortfolios in evaluating the  curriculum and student learning. Refereed paper presented at the Annual Program Meeting of the  Council on Social Work Education, New York City, NY.  Fitch, D. (2004, October). Designing information systems around decision making. Invited paper  presented at the Information Technology Adoption in the Nonprofit Sector Symposium, San  Francisco, CA.  Spencer, M., Grogan-Kaylor, A., Fitch, D., &amp; McBeath, B. (2003, January). The equivalence of the  behavior problem index across racial and ethnic groups. Refereed paper presented at the Society for  Social Work Research, Washington, DC.  Fitch, D. (2002, September). From data to intelligence: Introducing the intelligent organization.  Invited presentation at the University of Michigan School of Information Collaboratory for  Research on Electronic Work, Ann Arbor, MI.  Fitch, D. (2001, March). A description of the child protective services investigative decision making  context with implications for decision support system design. Refereed paper presented at the  Annual Program Meeting of the Council on Social Work Education, Dallas, TX.  Hernandez, S., &amp; Fitch, D. (2000, November). Ideological dislocation: Implications for mentoring new  minority social workers. Invited presentation, the 24th Annual NASW/Texas State Conference,  Fort Worth, TX.  DALE K. FITCH - Page 10 of 15    Fitch, D. (2000, October). Developing and evaluating a decision support system in child protective  services. Refereed paper presented at the 9th Annual Child Welfare League of America  Information Technology Conference, Atlanta, GA.  Fitch, D. (1999, March). The need for a systems based theory for the delivery of human services via the  Internet. Refereed paper presented at the 79th Annual Meeting of the Southwestern Social  Science Association, San Antonio, TX.  Frasier, L., Fitch, D., Bopp, K. The economic costs of Shaken Baby Syndrome survivors in Missouri.  Invited presentations at: 1. The Second National Conference on Shaken Baby Syndrome, Salt  Lake City, UT (1998, September). 2. The Wisconsin Conference on Shaken Babies: The  Interdisciplinary Challenge, Middleton, WI, (1998, March). 3. The Missouri Childrens Trust  Fund First Annual Conference on Child Abuse Prevention Leadership &amp; Policy, Jefferson City,  MO, (1997, November).  Fitch, D. (1997, October). Child abuse and neglect: A broad overview of the dynamics involved in the  screening, assessment, reporting, and diagnosis of suspected cases of child abuse and neglect. Invited  presentation to the University of Missouri Hospitals &amp; Clinics and broadcast over the Missouri  Telemedicine Network, Columbia, MO.  Fitch, D. Profiles of sexual abuse perpetrators. Invited presentation to the: 1. University of Missouri  Hospitals &amp; Clinics, Department of Child Health Grand Rounds, Columbia, MO (1995,  November). 2. SAFE/CARE training, St. Louis, MO (1996, April).  Fitch, D. (1995, October). Child sexual abuse and children with neurodevelopmental disorders. Invited  presentation to the University of Missouri College of Education, Columbia, MO.  Fitch, D. Hospital social work and child abuse. Invited presentations to: 1. Columbia Regional  Hospital, Columbia, MO (1994, March). 2. University of Missouri College of Education,  Columbia, MO (1994, April). 3. William Woods University, Fulton, MO (1994, October). 4.  Hedrick Medical Center, Chillicothe, MO (1994, December).  Schneider, H., &amp; Fitch, D. (1993, September). Child sexual abuse: Individual and family dynamics  and the implications for intervention. Invited presentation to the Office of Continuing Professional  Education, University of Missouri, Rolla, MO.    OTHER RELATED SCHOLARLY ACTIVITIES  2016  present  2013  2016  2012  present  2008  present  2007  present    Aotearoa New Zealand Social Work, board member  Editor-in-Chief, Journal of Technology in Human Services  Evaluation &amp; Program Planning, board member  Journal of Social Work Education, consulting editor  Social Work, consulting editor  DALE K. FITCH - Page 11 of 15    2006  2012  Journal of Technology in Human Services, associate editor  2006  present International Journal of Applied Systemic Studies, board member    Occasional Reviewer  Children and Youth Services Review, American Journal of Evaluation,  Educational Research and Evaluation, International Social Work, Systemic Practice and Action Research,  Journal of Public Child Welfare, Systems Research and Behavioral Science, Advances in Social Work    TEACHING EXPERIENCE  Graduate  Community and Organizational Dynamics  Organizational Issues in Child Welfare  Critical Issues in Child Welfare  Research Methods in Social Work  Professional Practice Seminar  Management, Community Organization &amp; Policy Practice  Management of Information Systems in Human Service Agencies  Social Work Practice with Community and Social Systems  Field Seminar  Evaluation in Social Work  Undergraduate  Community and Organizational Dynamics  Strategies of Direct Practice  Honors Field Seminar  Proseminar Interdisciplinary Studies (Freshman Interest Group)  Guest lectures for: PhD Research Methods Seminar, MSW Research Methods, Communities &amp;  Information    DOCTORAL COMMITTEE MEMBERSHIPS  2013-2016  2009-2012    2009-2011    2006-2008  2005-2007    Anita Kiessling-Caver, \xe2\x80\x9cPerceptions of Childhood as Indicators of Early  Attachment Deficits among Individuals with a History of Violent Crime.\xe2\x80\x9d (chair)  Michelle Kaiser, \xe2\x80\x9cCultivating a Landscape for Food Justice: Using Food  Environment Indicators to Inform Community-Based Intervention Strategies.\xe2\x80\x9d  (member)  Paul Foreman, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Impact of Eligibility Guideline Changes in the Missouris  State Children Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) on Poor Working Families  with Children with Asthma.\xe2\x80\x9d (member)  Melita Vaz, \xe2\x80\x9cUnderstanding Parental Theories about Childrens Health.\xe2\x80\x9d  (methodologist)  Skip Barcy, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Relationship of Computer Attitude to Reported Use and  Observed Behavioral Proficiency.\xe2\x80\x9d (methodologist)    DALE K. FITCH - Page 12 of 15    PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS &amp; CREDENTIALS  National Association of Social Workers, 1984 - present  American Professional Society on the Abuse of Children, 1991 - 1998  Missouri Chapter of the National Committee to Prevent Child Abuse Board Member, 1996   1998  Council on Social Work Education, 1998  present  Texas State Board of Social Worker Examiners, Licensed Master Social Worker, 1998-2001,  License Number 10760  Missouri Board of Licensed Clinical Social Workers, 1991  1998, License Number 1108  Oklahoma Board of Licensed Clinical Social Workers, 1986  1991, License Number 1223    REPRESENTATIVE SERVICE  University  University of Missouri  2016  Present  2016  Present  2014  Present  2014  Present  2011  Present  2013 Spring    Distance Education Strategic Planning Committee  ET@MO Advisory Board  MU Assessment Advisory Committee  Mizzou Online Advisory Council  MU Family Friendly Campus Committee  Committee Chair, 2012  2014  Review Committee for Provost Outstanding Junior Faculty Teaching Award    College of Human Environmental Sciences  2016  Present HES Task Force on Inclusivity and Diversity (Committee Chair)  Faculty Council on College Policy  2014  2016  2011 Spring HES Graduate Fellowships Committee    University of Missouri School of Social Work  2012  2016  Scholarship Committee  2011  2012  MSW Research sub-committee  2010  2016  MSW committee  2010  Present Off-campus committee  2009  Present BSW committee  2009  2016 ePortfolio workgroup  2009  2014 Title IV-E program committee    University of Michigan  2006  2004  2003  2008    Member, Search Committee, Director of UM Non-profit Management Center  Member, University Library Committee  Member, Chair (2004 - 2005), University of Michigan Campus-Wide ePortfolio  Special Interest Group  DALE K. FITCH - Page 13 of 15    University of Michigan School of Social Work  2004  2008  2005  2008  2005  2008  2006  2004  2005  2004  2005  2004  2005  2002  2003  2002  2001  2006  2001  2002    Management Workgroup  Alternative Reaffirmation Committee  Portfolio Workgroup  Executive Committee Annual Review  Curriculum Committee  Staff Recognition Committee, Chair  Vision Task Group  Child &amp; Family Workgroup; Macro Workgroup  Student Grievance Committee  Information Technology Committee  Foundation Workgroup    Profession  Committees  2014  2016    Teaching and Learning Social Work Online track co-chair for the Social Work  Distance Education Conference  2011  2015  Technology in Social Work Education and Practice track co-chair for the Council  on Social Work Education Annual Program Meeting  2011  2012  Council on Social Work Education Task Force on eLearning Standards  Human Service Information Technology Applications, Board member; Secretary,  2007  2016  2011 - 2015  2004  2006  Association for Research on Nonprofit Organizations and Voluntary Action  Recruitment Committee  2003  Present Abstracts Reviewer, Council on Social Work Education Annual Program Meeting    Community/State/National    Board Member, Welcome Home, Inc., 2015 to present  AIRS Linked Open Vocabulary Workgroup, 2014 - present  Open Referral Task Force, 2012 - present  State of Missouri, Department of Social Services, Childrens Division, Child and Family  Services Review Committee, 2009  present  Family Justice Organization National Advisory Board, 2008  2009  Washtenaw County Community Collaborative Child Protection Workgroup, 2007 - 2009  Vista Maria Professional Advisory Group, 2003  2009  Washtenaw County 2-1-1 Advisory Board, 2004  2009  Core Leadership Team Member, Washtenaw County Blueprint on Aging, 2006  2009  Ann Arbor Council of Private Agencies, 2001  2006  Advisory Committee, Southeast Michigan Information Center, 2001  2004  Board Member, Missouri Chapter of the National Committee to Prevent Child Abuse, 1996   1998  DALE K. FITCH - Page 14 of 15    DALE K. FITCH - Page 15 of 15"
</cv>
