<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cv>
"Curriculum Vitae  <label type="Name">Tiffany Padberg</label>  April 21, 2017    1    Contact  Institute for Quantitative Social Science  Harvard University  1737 Cambridge Street  Cambridge, Massachusetts 02138  Direct: (123)345-7890  Assistant: (123)345-7890    2    GaryKing.org  @KingGary    King@Harvard.edu    Education    Ph.D., Political Science, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1984.  M.A., Political Science, University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1981.  B.A., Summa Cum Laude; Highest Honors in Political Science; State University of New  York at New Paltz, 1980.    3    Positions    Albert J. Weatherhead III University Professor, Harvard University, 2009 to the present.  David Florence Professor of Government, Harvard University, 2002 to 2009.  Professor of Government, Department of Government, Harvard University, 1990 to 2002.  John L. Loeb Associate Professor of the Social Sciences, Department of Government,  Harvard University, 1989.  Associate Professor, Department of Government, Harvard University, 1987 to 1989.  Visiting Assistant Professor, Department of Political Science, University of Wisconsin,  Madison, Summer 1985.  Assistant Professor, Department of Politics, New York University, September, 1984 to  1987.    Gary King    4    2    Honorary Societies    Elected Member, National Academy of Social Insurance, 2014.  Elected Member, National Academy of Sciences, 2010.  Elected Fellow, American Statistical Association, 2009.  Elected Fellow, Society for Political Methodology, 2008.  Elected Fellow, American Association for the Advancement of Science, 2004.  Elected Fellow, American Academy of Political and Social Science, 2004.  Elected Fellow, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1998.  Guggenheim Fellow, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 19941995.    5    Prizes and Awards    Best Paper Award, Political Communication Division, International Communication Association, 2017, for \xe2\x80\x9cHow the Chinese Government Fabricates Social Media Posts for  Strategic Distraction, not Engaged Argument\xe2\x80\x9d with Margaret Roberts and Jennifer Pan.  Dartmouth Ventures Entrepreneurship Competition, 2nd place, for Thresher, with Rebecca  Fair, 2015.  Warren E. Miller Award for Meritorious Service to the Social Sciences, Inter-University  Consortium for Political and Social Research, 2015.  Accelerator Award, Harvard University, Office of Technology Development, for \xe2\x80\x9cLet Machines Score so Teachers can Teach,\xe2\x80\x9d which became Perusall.com, with Eric Mazur, 2015.  MPSA Kellogg/Notre Dame Award, from the Midwest Political Science Association, for  the best paper in Comparative Politics, 2014, for \xe2\x80\x9cReverse Engineering Chinese Censorship through Randomized Experimentation and Participant Observation,\xe2\x80\x9d with Margaret  Roberts and Jennifer Pan.  Statistical Software Award, Society for Political Methodology, 2014, for Amelia II, by  James Honaker, Gary King, and Matthew Blackwell.  Highly Cited Researcher, and listed in Worlds Most Influential Scientific Minds, ThompsonReuters, 2014.  Everett Mendelsohn Excellence in Mentoring Award, Harvard Graduate Student Council,  2011.  Career Achievement Award, Society for Political Methodology, 2010.  Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters, State University of New York at New Paltz, 2010.  New Hot Paper, for the most-cited paper in Economics and Business in the last two months  among papers published in the last year, for \xe2\x80\x9cMisunderstandings among Experimentalists    Gary King    3    and Observationalists about Causal Inference\xe2\x80\x9d by Kosuke Imai, Gary King, and Elizabeth  A. Stuart, named by Thomson Reuters ScienceWatch, 2009.  Miller-Converse Lecturer, Center for Political Studies, Institute for Social Research, University of Michigan, 2009.  Warren Miller Prize for the best article published in Political Analysis, for \xe2\x80\x9cMatching  as Nonparametric Preprocessing for Reducing Model Dependence in Parametric Causal  Inference\xe2\x80\x9d by Daniel E. Ho, Kosuke Imai, Gary King, and Elizabeth Stuart, awarded by  the Society for Political Methodology and Oxford University Press in 2008.  Fast Breaking Paper, for the article with the largest percentage increase in citations among  those in the top 1% of total citations across the social sciences in the last two years, for  \xe2\x80\x9cMatching as Nonparametric Preprocessing for Reducing Model Dependence in Parametric  Causal Inference\xe2\x80\x9d by Daniel E. Ho, Kosuke Imai, Gary King, and Elizabeth Stuart, named  by Thomson Reuters ScienceWatch, 2008.  APSA (ITP Section) Best Instructional Political Science Website Award, for the Dataverse  Network Project, by Gary King, Merce Crosas, and the Dataverse Network team, 2008.  Elected to the Nominating Committee for the American Association for the Advancement  of Science, Section on Social, Economic, and Political Sciences, 2/20-20072/22/2010.  Named in 2006 to ISIHighlyCited.coms list of the most highly cited researchers in the  social sciences, Thomson Reuters.  The McGraw-Hill Award for the best journal article on law and courts written by a political  scientist and published during the previous calendar year for \xe2\x80\x9cThe Supreme Court During  Crisis: How War Affects only Non-War Cases\xe2\x80\x9d by Lee Epstein, Daniel E. Ho, Gary King,  and Jeffrey A. Segal, 2006.  Law and Society Association Prize, Runner up, to \xe2\x80\x9crecognize exceptional scholarship in  the field of sociolegal studies for an article published in the previous two years,\xe2\x80\x9d for \xe2\x80\x9cThe  Supreme Court During Crisis: How War Affects only Non-War Cases\xe2\x80\x9d by Lee Epstein,  Daniel E. Ho, Gary King, and Jeffrey A. Segal, 2006.  Best Instructional Innovation in the Social Sciences or Social History, Honorable Mention,  2005 ICPSR Prize, for \xe2\x80\x9cPublication, Publication,\xe2\x80\x9d by Gary King.  Pi Sigma Alpha Award, for the best paper delivered at the previous years MWPSA Conference, for \xe2\x80\x9cThe Supreme Court During Crisis: How War Affects only Non-War Cases\xe2\x80\x9d  by Lee Epstein, Daniel E. Ho, Gary King, and Jeffrey A. Segal, 2005.  Robert H. Durr Award, for \xe2\x80\x9cthe best paper applying quantitative methods to a substantive  problem\xe2\x80\x9d at the previous years MWPSA Conference, for \xe2\x80\x9cThe Supreme Court During  Crisis: How War Affects only Non-War Cases\xe2\x80\x9d by Lee Epstein, Daniel E. Ho, Gary King,  and Jeffrey A. Segal, 2005.  APSA Research Software Award, for The Virtual Data Center, by Micah Altman, Gary  King, and Sidney Verba, http://TheData.org, 2005.  American Judicature Society Award, Honorable Mention, for the best paper presented at  the previous years meetings of the American, Midwest, Northeastern, Southern, Southwest, or Western Political Science Associations, for \xe2\x80\x9cThe Supreme Court During Crisis:    Gary King    4    How War Affects only Non-War Cases\xe2\x80\x9d by Lee Epstein, Daniel E. Ho, Gary King, and  Jeffrey A. Segal, 2005.  Elected Vice President, American Political Science Association, for 20032004.  Listed in American Political Scientists: A Dictionary (2002), giving the \xe2\x80\x9cconsensus group  of 193 political scientists who have made the most important theoretical contributions\xe2\x80\x9d to  the discipline \xe2\x80\x9cfrom its beginnings in the late-19th century to the present\xe2\x80\x9d.  ISI Emerging Research Front Article, for authoring an article cited more often in the  fields of Psychiatry and Psychology than any other, October, 2002 (for Gary King, James  Honaker, Anne Joseph, and Kenneth Scheves \xe2\x80\x9cAnalyzing Incomplete Political Science  Data: An Alternative Algorithm for Multiple Imputation,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science  Review ), Thomson Reuters ScienceWatch.  Clifford C. Clogg Memorial Lecturer in Sociology and Statistics, Pennsylvania State University, 2002.  Vision Distinguished Lecturer, Florida State University, 2001.  Outstanding Statistical Application Award, for the outstanding application of statistics  in any substantive field, for \xe2\x80\x9cNot Asked and Not Answered: Multiple Imputation for  Multiple Surveys,\xe2\x80\x9d with Andrew Gelman and Chuanhai Liu, from the American Statistical  Association, 2000.  The Gosnell Prize, for the best work in political methodology presented at any political  science conference in the preceding year, for \xe2\x80\x9cImproving Quantitative Studies of International Conflict: A Conjecture,\xe2\x80\x9d with Nathaniel Beck and Langche Zeng, 1999.  The Okidata Best Research Software Award, for \xe2\x80\x9cClarify: Software for Interpreting and  Presenting Statistical Results,\xe2\x80\x9d with Michael Tomz and Jason Wittenberg, 1999, from the  American Political Science Association.  The Okidata Best Research Web Site Award, for the Record of American Democracy  project and the Harvard-MIT Data Center, 1999, from the American Political Science  Association.  Pi Sigma Alpha Award for the best paper (\xe2\x80\x9cA Statistical Model for Multiparty Electoral  Data\xe2\x80\x9d with Jonathan Katz) at the previous years meetings of the Midwest Political Science  Association, 1998.  The Donald Campbell Award for the \xe2\x80\x9coutstanding methodological innovator in public  policy studies,\xe2\x80\x9d from the Policy Studies Organization, 1997.  The Gosnell Prize, for the best work in political methodology presented at any political  science conference in the preceding year, for the work published as A Solution to the  Ecological Inference Problem: Reconstructing Individual Behavior from Aggregate Data  (Princeton University Press, 1997).  Elected President, Society for Political Methodology, 19971999.  Alumnus of the Year, State University of New York at New Paltz Alumni Association,  1997.    Gary King    5    The APSA Research Software Award for \xe2\x80\x9cEzI: A(n Easy) Program for Ecological Inference\xe2\x80\x9d (with Kenneth Benoit) from the American Political Science Association, Computer  Section, 1997.  State University of New York Alumni Honor Roll (an award created to honor alumni who  demonstrate outstanding professional achievement and significant contributions to higher  education and/or public service), from the Chancellor of the State University of New York,  1997.  The Heinz Eulau Award, for the best article published in the American Political Science Review, from the American Political Science Association, for \xe2\x80\x9cEnhancing Democracy  Through Legislative Redistricting,\xe2\x80\x9d (with Andrew Gelman) Vol. 88, No. 3 (September,  1994): Pp. 541559.  Elected Vice President, Society for Political Methodology, 19951997.  Visiting Fellow, Nuffield College, Oxford University, Summer, 1994.  The APSA Research Software Award for \xe2\x80\x9cCOUNT: A Program for Estimating Event  Count and Duration Regressions,\xe2\x80\x9d from the American Political Science Association, Computer Section, 1994.  The Mills Award, for the \xe2\x80\x9coutstanding contributor in the field of public policy under age  35,\xe2\x80\x9d from the Policy Studies Organization, 1993.  Pi Sigma Alpha Award for the best paper (\xe2\x80\x9cWhy Do U.S. Presidential Election Polls Vary  So Much When the Vote is So Predictable?\xe2\x80\x9d with Andrew Gelman) at the previous years  meetings of the Midwest Political Science Association, 1993.  The APSA Research Software Award for \xe2\x80\x9cJudgeIt: A Program for Evaluating Electoral  Systems and Redistricting Plans,\xe2\x80\x9d (with Andrew Gelman), from the American Political  Science Association, Computer Section, 1992.  Curriculum Development Challenge Award, \xe2\x80\x9cUndergraduate Research Participation in Political Science,\xe2\x80\x9d New York University, 1987.  Research Challenge Award, \xe2\x80\x9cPublic Opinion and Executive Behavior: Toward a New Presidency Research Agenda,\xe2\x80\x9d New York University, 1986.  University Fellowship, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 198384.    6    Research Grants    \xe2\x80\x9cCitation++: Data Citation, Provenance, and Documentation,\xe2\x80\x9d National Science Foundation, ACI-1448123, 1/01/201512/31/2017, With Margo Seltzer and Merce Crosas,  ($300,000).  \xe2\x80\x9cApplying Theoretical Advances in Privacy to Computational Social Science Practice,\xe2\x80\x9d  Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1230456789, G-2123-456789 4/01/20159/30/2017 with Salil  Vadham, Urs Gasser, Merce Crosas, and Micah Altman ($616,000).    Gary King    6    \xe2\x80\x9cPreparing Social Science Research Infrastructure for the Potential Inversion of Its Largest  Successes and Failures,\xe2\x80\x9d Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, G-2123-456789, with Merce Crosas,  12/31/20155/31/2017, ($751,941).  \xe2\x80\x9cAlfred P. Sloan Fellowships: Toward the Creation of Interdisciplinary Fellowships in  Data Science,\xe2\x80\x9d Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, G-2123-34567890, with Richard McCullough,  1/01/20166/30/2018, ($124,994).  \xe2\x80\x9cRAPID: Measuring the Intent of Chinese Leaders through Censorship Behavior,\xe2\x80\x9d National Science Foundation, SES-1500086, With Jennifer Pan and Margaret Roberts, 3/01/2015  2/29/2016 ($200,000).  \xe2\x80\x9cCausal Inference Methods for Estimating Long Term Health Effects of Air Quality Regulations,\xe2\x80\x9d Health Effects Institute/Environmental Protection Agency, 4909-RFA11-1/12-3;  CR-83467701, with Corwin Zigler et al., 5/01/2012 10/31/15, ($1,033,958).  \xe2\x80\x9cStatistically Defensible Comparison of Similar but Disparate Tests,\xe2\x80\x9d Charles River Analytics Inc./Department of Defense SC1220801 EVIDENT; FA9550-13-C-0028, 2/15/2013  11/14/2013, with Wayne Thornton et al. ($75,000).  \xe2\x80\x9cA Bridge from Publishing Words to Publishing Data,\xe2\x80\x9d Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, G2123-456789, 1/1/201512/31/2017, with Merce Crosas, Tom Carsey, and Jonathan Crabtree ($845,000).  \xe2\x80\x9cPrivacy for Social Science Research,\xe2\x80\x9d National Science Foundation #CNS-1237235, 10/01/2012  9/30/2017, with Salil Vadhan, Edoardo Airoldi, Phillip Malone, Latanya Sweeney, ($5,992,707).  \xe2\x80\x9cBetterBirth: A Trial of the WHO Safe Childbirth Checklist Program,\xe2\x80\x9d Gates Foundation #OPP1017378, 5/12/20114/28/2015, with Atul Gawande, Jonathan Spector, Stuart  Lipsitz, Sue Goldie, and Stephen Resch, ($14,149,388).  \xe2\x80\x9cCenter for Historical Information and Analysis (CHIA),\xe2\x80\x9d National Science Foundation  #BCS-1244667, 1/1/1312/31/2015, with Patrick Manning, ($91,600).  \xe2\x80\x9cDataBridge \xe2\x80\x94 A Sociometric System for Long-tail Science Data Collections,\xe2\x80\x9d National  Science Foundation #OCI-1247602, 11/1/201210/31/2016, with Arcot Rajasekar, Thomas  Carsey, Hye-Chung Kum, Howard Lander, Sharlini Sankaran, Justin Zahn, ($463,263).  Disney Research Grant, 2012, ($35,000).  \xe2\x80\x9cHelping Journals to Upgrade Data Publication for Reusable Research,\xe2\x80\x9d 2012-3-2, Alfred P. Sloan Foundation #219264, 6/1/20121/1/2015, with Micah Altman and John  Willinsky ($1,058,994).  \xe2\x80\x9cText Clustering,\xe2\x80\x9d Amazon Web Services in Education Research Grant, 2011.  \xe2\x80\x9cMeasuring, Understanding, and Responding to Covert Social Networks,\xe2\x80\x9d Department of  Defense, Multidisciplinary University Research Initiative (MURI) #W91INF-11-1-0036DOD35CAP, 11/23/201011/22/2016 with Patrick Wolfe, Edo Airoldi, Mung Chiang,  David Lazer, Devavrat Shah, and Burton Singer ($6,240,927).  Institute for Museum and Library Services, \xe2\x80\x9cSimple Verified Distributed Preservation: A  Policy Based Archival Replication System for Libraries, Archives, and Museums using a    Gary King    7    Virtual Private LOCKSS,\xe2\x80\x9d LG-05-09-0041-09, with Mark Abrahamson, Ken Bollen, and  Nancy McGovern, 10/1/20099/30/2012 ($823,016).  National Science Foundation, CDI-Type II: Collaborative Research, \xe2\x80\x9cBibliographic Knowledge Network,\xe2\x80\x9d DMS-0835500, with James Pitman et al., 10/1/20089/30/2011 ($1,211,433).  Library of Congress, \xe2\x80\x9cExtension to the Digital Social Science Acquisitions and Preservation  Partnership,\xe2\x80\x9d with Myron Gutmann, Mark Abrahamson, and Ken Bollen, 2009-2010,  ($274,832).  Library of Congress, \xe2\x80\x9cExtension to the Digital Social Science Acquisitions and Preservation  Partnership,\xe2\x80\x9d with Myron Gutmann, Mark Abrahamson, and Ken Bollen, 2007-2009,  ($710,000).  Initiative for Innovative Computing, \xe2\x80\x9cGenePattern and the Dataverse Network,\xe2\x80\x9d with Jill  Mesirov, 9/1/20068/31/2008, ($250,000).  Time Sharing Experiments for the Social Sciences, \xe2\x80\x9cPriming to Increase the Information  Content in Survey Responses,\xe2\x80\x9d with Daniel Hopkins (survey time).  Library of Congress, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Digital Social Science Acquisitions and Preservation Partnership,\xe2\x80\x9d PA#NDP03-1, 9/1/2004-3/30/2010, with Myron Gutmann, Ken Bollen, David  Weakliem, and Louise Richardson ($2,037,595).  Ministry of Health, Mexico, \xe2\x80\x9cEvaluation of the System for Social Protection in Health,\xe2\x80\x9d  8/1/200412/31/2006, ($1,049,981).  National Institutes of Health, National Institute on Aging grant, \xe2\x80\x9cSoftware Development  for Resolving Interpersonal Incomparability in Survey Research,\xe2\x80\x9d Supp. to \xe2\x80\x9cAdapting Statistical Methods for Public Health Research,\xe2\x80\x9d P01 AG17625-01 7/20038/2005 ($28,659).  Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, \xe2\x80\x9cScholars in Health Policy Research Program,\xe2\x80\x9d 9/2003  8/2007, with Nicholas Christakis and Joe Newhouse ($4,564,391).  World Health Organization, \xe2\x80\x9cImproved Methods of Demographic Forecasting,\xe2\x80\x9d 9/2001  8/2003 ($90,000).  Swiss Peace Foundation grant, \xe2\x80\x9cInternational Relations Events Data and Methods Development,\xe2\x80\x9d 9/2002-8/2003 (two research fellows).  Robert Wood Johnson Foundation planning grant, \xe2\x80\x9cScholars in Health Policy Research  Program,\xe2\x80\x9d 9/20028/2003, with Nicholas Christakis, Jennifer Hochschild, and Joe Newhouse ($199,967).  National Science Foundation grant, \xe2\x80\x9cA Feasible Uniform Standard for Deep Citation of  Social Science Data,\xe2\x80\x9d grant SES-0112072, 9/1/20018/31/06, with Jim Alt and Micah  Altman ($805,102).  Toyota Foundation, \xe2\x80\x9cProjecting International Conflict,\xe2\x80\x9d 6/25/016/25/02 (a graduate research fellowship).  National Institutes of Health, National Institute on Aging grant, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Global Burden of  Disease in Aging Populations: Adapting Statistical Methods for Public Health Research,\xe2\x80\x9d    Gary King    8    with Christopher J.L. Murray et al., grant 1 P01 AG17625-01, 9/30/20008/31/2005  ($8,656,009).  Weatherhead Initiative grant, \xe2\x80\x9cMilitary Conflict as a Public Health Perspective,\xe2\x80\x9d Weatherhead Center for International Affairs, with Christopher J.L. Murray, 20002002 ($250,000).  World Health Organization and the National Institutes of Aging grant, \xe2\x80\x9cForecasting Death  by Age, Sex, Cause, and Country,\xe2\x80\x9d 19982001 ($529,040).  Digital Library Initiative grant (sponsored by the National Science Foundation, Defense  Advanced Research Projects Agency, National Library of Medicine, Library of Congress,  National Endowment for the Humanities, and the National Aeronautics &amp; Space Administration) for the \xe2\x80\x9cVirtual Data Center Project\xe2\x80\x9d (see http://TheData.org) with Micah  Altman and Sidney Verba et al., grant IIS-9874747, 7/1/19996/31/2004 ($2,400,000).  National Science Foundation Grant, Co-PI, \xe2\x80\x9cSummer Meetings of the Society for Political  Methodology,\xe2\x80\x9d with Charles Franklin, SBR-9905798, ($68,976).  Intel Corporation, \xe2\x80\x9cGeospatial Liboratory Project,\xe2\x80\x9d with Micah Altman, Susan Lee, Paul  Bergen, David Cobb, Arlene Olivero, Thomas Parris, and William Wei, ($150,000).  ICPSR, Data Documentation Initiative Test, with Micah Altman, Michael McDonald, and  Michael Ting, ($1,750).  National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure, supercomputer allocation grant for \xe2\x80\x9cEcological Inference and Voting for the Nazis,\xe2\x80\x9d with Ori Rosen and Martin  Tanner, June 1998 to May 1999.  Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (Division of Diabetes Translation), 15 July  199814 July 1999, ($90,311).  Global Forum for Health Research grant, 19981999, ($10,000).  National Science Foundation Grant SBR-9729884, \xe2\x80\x9cMissing Information in Survey Research,\xe2\x80\x9d 1 March 199828 February 2000 ($175,000).  National Science Foundation Grant SBR-9321212, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Record of American Democracy,  1984-1990,\xe2\x80\x9d 1 March 199431 August 1997, ($140,996).  Fairness for the 90s Foundation Grant, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Record of American Democracy, 1984-1990.\xe2\x80\x9d  (\xe2\x89\x88$3,500,000).  National Science Foundation Grant SBR-9223637, \xe2\x80\x9cGeneralizing Multiple Imputation to  Time Series Data, with Application to Survey Research and Evaluating Electoral Systems and Redistricting Plans,\xe2\x80\x9d 1 August 199331 January 1996, (with Andrew Gelman),  $70,000.  National Science Foundation Grant SES-89-09201, \xe2\x80\x9cModeling Representation in DistrictBased Electoral Systems,\xe2\x80\x9d 1 July 198931 December 1991 ($78,429).  National Science Foundation Grant, Co-PI, \xe2\x80\x9cPolitical Methodology Summer Workshops,\xe2\x80\x9d  1 June 19901 January 1992 ($37,601, with John Jackson, Larry Bartels, Henry Brady,  Stanley Feldman, and Gary King).    Gary King    9    Smith Richardson Foundation Grant, \xe2\x80\x9cRepresentation and Gerrymandering in American  Electoral Systems,\xe2\x80\x9d 1 August 19891 September 1990 ($45,227).  National Science Foundation Grant, \xe2\x80\x9cDemocratic Representation in District-Based Electoral Systems: A Stochastic Model of Legislative Redistricting,\xe2\x80\x9d 1 February 198831 July  1989 ($37,000).  National Science Foundation, URP grant, Summer, 1979.  Citizen Participation in Government Foundation, 9/19795/1980.    7    Books    King, Gary; Kay Schlozman; and Norman Nie, eds., The Future of Political Science: 100  Perspectives, New York: Routledge Press, 2009.  Girosi, Federico and Gary King. Demographic Forecasting, Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2008.  King, Gary; Ori Rosen; and Martin A. Tanner, eds., Ecological Inference: New Methodological Strategies, New York: Cambridge University Press, 2004.  King, Gary. A Solution to the Ecological Inference Problem: Reconstructing Individual  Behavior from Aggregate Data, Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1997, (replication  dataset: ICPSR s1132).  King, Gary; Robert O. Keohane; and Sidney Verba. Designing Social Inquiry: Scientific  Inference in Qualitative Research. Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1994.  King, Gary. Unifying Political Methodology: The Likelihood Theory of Statistical Inference. Cambridge, England and New York: Cambridge University Press, 1989. Reprinted,  Ann Arbor: University of Michigan Press, 1998.  King, Gary and Lyn Ragsdale. The Elusive Executive: Discovering Statistical Patterns in  the Presidency. Washington, D.C.: Congressional Quarterly Press, 1988.  Brace, Paul; Christine Harrington; and Gary King. The Presidency in American Politics.  New York and London: New York University Press, 1989. Paperback published in 1990.    8    Articles    King, Gary; Jennifer Pan; and Margaret E. Roberts. In press, 2017. \xe2\x80\x9cHow the Chinese Government Fabricates Social Media Posts for Strategic Distraction, not Engaged  Argument,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science Review, 2017. http://j.mp/1Txxiz1.  King, Gary; Patrick Lam; and Margaret E. Roberts. In press, 2017. \xe2\x80\x9cComputer-Assisted  Keyword and Document Set Discovery from Unstructured Text,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of  Political Science, http://j.mp/1qdVqhx    Gary King    10    Schwab, Michail; Hendrik Strobelt; James Tompkin; Colin Fredericks; Connor Huff; Dana  Higgins; Anton Strezhnev; Mayya Komisarchik; Gary King; and Hanspeter Pfister. In  Press, 2017. \xe2\x80\x9cbooc.io: An Education System with Hierarchical Concept Maps,\xe2\x80\x9d IEEE  Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, PP(99).  Semrau, Katherine; Lisa R. Hirschhorn; Bhala Kodkany; Jonathan Spector; Danielle E.  Tuller; Gary King; Stuart Lisptiz; Narender Sharma; Vinay P. Singh; Bharath Kumar;  Neelam Dhingra-Kumar; Rebecca Firestone; Vishwajeet Kumar; Atul Gawande. In Press.  \xe2\x80\x9cEffectiveness of the WHO Safe Childbirth Checklist Program in Reducing Severe Maternal, Fetal, and Newborn Harm: Study Protocol for a Matched-Pair, Cluster-Randomized  Controlled Trial in Uttar Pradesh, India,\xe2\x80\x9d Trials.  King, Gary; Christopher Lucas; and Richard Nielsen. In press, 2016. \xe2\x80\x9cThe BalanceSample Size Frontier in Matching Methods for Causal Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of  Political Science, Copy at http://j.mp/1dRDMrE.  Gilbert, Daniel; Gary King; Stephen Pettigrew; and Timothy Wilson. 2016. \xe2\x80\x9cComment  on Estimating the Reproducibility of Psychological Science,\xe2\x80\x9d Science, 6277, 351: 1037a1038a. Copy at http://j.mp/21LW9c8.  King, Gary. 2016. \xe2\x80\x9cPreface: Big Data is Not About the Data!,\xe2\x80\x9d In Computational Social  Science: Discovery and Prediction, edited by R. Michael Alvarez, Cambridge: Cambridge  University Press, 2016. Copy at http://j.mp/1PP466V.  King, Gary. 2016. \xe2\x80\x9cThe C-SPAN Archives as The Policymaking Record of American  Representative Democracy: A Foreword,\xe2\x80\x9d In Exploring the C-SPAN Archives: Advancing  the Research Agenda, edited by Robert X Browning, West Lafayette, IN: Purdue University  Press. Copy at http://j.mp/1PUq9No.  Kashin, Konstantin; Gary King; and Samir Soneji. 2015. \xe2\x80\x9cSystematic Bias and Nontransparency in US Social Security Administration Forecasts,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Economic Perspectives, Vol. 29, No. 2 (Spring, 2015): Pp. 239258, Copy at http://j.mp/1ITZ6Mw.  Kashin, Konstantin; Gary King; and Samir Soneji. 2015. \xe2\x80\x9cExplaining Systematic Bias  and Nontransparency in US Social Security Administration Forecasts,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis,  Vol. 23, No. 3 (Summer, 2015): Pp. 336362, Copy at http://j.mp/1GStulL.  Blackwell, Matthew; James Honaker; and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Unified Approach to Measurement Error and Missing Data: Overview,\xe2\x80\x9d Sociological Methods and Research, In press,  Copy at http://j.mp/jqdj72.  Blackwell, Matthew; James Honaker; and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Unified Approach to Measurement Error and MissingData: Details and Extensions,\xe2\x80\x9d Sociological Methods and Research,  In press, Copy at http://j.mp/1iOvDUD.  King, Gary, and Margaret Roberts. \xe2\x80\x9cHow Robust Standard Errors Expose Methodological  Problems They Do Not Fix, and What to Do About It,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 23, No. 2  (2015): Pp. 159179, Copy at http://j.mp/InK5jU.  King, Gary; Jennifer Pan; and Margaret Roberts. \xe2\x80\x9cReverse Engineering Chinese Censorship: Randomized Experimentation and Participant Observation,\xe2\x80\x9d Science, Vol. 345, Issue  6199 (22 August 2014): 110, Copy at http://j.mp/16Nvzge.    Gary King    11    Lazer, David; Ryan Kennedy; Gary King; and Alessandro Vespignani. 2014. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Parable  of Google Flu: Traps in Big Data Analysis,\xe2\x80\x9d Science Vol. 343, No. 14 (March, 2014): Pp.  12031205, Copy at http://j.mp/1ii4ETo  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cRestructuring the Social Sciences: Reflections from Harvards Institute for  Quantitative Social Science,\xe2\x80\x9d PS: Political Science and Politics, Vol. 47, No. 1 (2014): Pp.  165172, Copy at http://j.mp/17Cobeu  King, Gary; and Sen, Maya. \xe2\x80\x9cHow Social Science Research Can Improve Teaching,\xe2\x80\x9d  PS: Political Science and Politics, Vol. 46, No. 3 (July, 2013): 671679, Copy at http:  //j.mp/NFVja6  King, Gary; Jennifer Pan; and Molly Roberts. \xe2\x80\x9cHow Censorship in China Allows Government Criticism but Silences Collective Expression,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science Review,  Vol. 107, No. 2 (May, 2013): 326-343, Copy at http://j.mp/LdVXqN.  King, Gary; and Maya Sen. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Troubled Future of Colleges and Universities,\xe2\x80\x9d PS:  Political Science and Politics, Vol., 46, no. 1 (2013): Pp. 81113, Copy at http://j.mp/  U82gj2  Soneji, Samir; and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cStatistical Security for Social Security,\xe2\x80\x9d Demography  (2012), Vol. 49, No. 3: Pp. 1037-1060, copy at http://j.mp/oi27uz.  King, Gary, and Samir Soneji. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Future of Death in America.\xe2\x80\x9d Demographic Research  Vol. 25, No. 1 (2011): Pp. 138, copy at http://j.mp/iXUpBv.  Iacus, Stefano M.; Gary King; and Giuseppe Porro. \xe2\x80\x9cCausal Inference Without Balance  Checking: Coarsened Exact Matching.\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis (2011), copy at http://j.mp/  iUUwyH.  King, Gary; Richard Nielsen; and Aaron Wells. \xe2\x80\x9cLetter to the Editor on the Medicare  Health Support Pilot Program (by McCall and Cromwell).\xe2\x80\x9d New England Journal of  Medicine 366, no. 7 (16 February 2012): 667, copy at http://j.mp/xECMXz.  Honaker, James; Gary King; and Matthew Blackwell. \xe2\x80\x9cAmelia II: A Program for Missing  Data,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software, Vol. 45, No. 7 (December, 2011), http://www.  jstatsoft.org/v45/i07/.  Goldstein, Edward; Benjamin J. Cowling; Allison E. Aiello; Saki Takahashi; Gary King;  Ying Lu; and Marc Lipsitch. \xe2\x80\x9cEstimating Incidence Curves of Several Infections Using  Symptom Surveillance Data,\xe2\x80\x9d PLoS ONE, 6 (2011): e23380, copy at http://j.mp/rnFl0z.  Wand, Jonathan; Gary King; and Olivia Lau. \xe2\x80\x9cAnchors: Software for Anchoring Vignettes  Data.\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software 42 (2011): 1-25, copy at http://j.mp/m5tITE.  King, Gary; Richard Nielsen; Carter Coberley; James E. Pope; and Aaron Wells. \xe2\x80\x9cAvoiding Randomization Failure in Program Evaluation,\xe2\x80\x9d Population Health Management, Vol.,  14, No. 1 (2011): S11-S22.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cEnsuring the Data Rich Future of the Social Sciences,\xe2\x80\x9d Science, Vol. 331 (11  February 2011): 719-721.  Grimmer, Justin and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cGeneral Purpose Computer-Assisted Clustering and  Conceptualization,\xe2\x80\x9d Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 3 February (2011).    Gary King    12    Iacus, Stefano M.; Gary King; and Giuseppe Porro. \xe2\x80\x9cMultivariate Matching Methods That  are Monotonic Imbalance Bounding,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of the American Statistical Association, Vol.  106 (2011): Pp. 345361.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cInference in Case-Control Studies,\xe2\x80\x9d in Shein-Chung Chow,  ed., Encyclopedia of Biopharmaceutical Statistics, 3rd edition. New York: Marcel Dekker,  2010.  King, Gary; Ying Lu; and Kenji Shibuya. \xe2\x80\x9cDesigning Verbal Autopsy Studies,\xe2\x80\x9d Population  Health Metrics, (2010) 8:19.  Stevens, Gretchen; Gary King; and Kenji Shibuya. \xe2\x80\x9cDeaths From Heart Failure: Using Coarsened Exact Matching to Correct Cause of Death Statistics,\xe2\x80\x9d Population Health  Metrics, 2010 Vol. 8, No. 6.  Blackwell, Matthew; Stefano M. Iacus; Gary King; and Giuseppe Porro, \xe2\x80\x9ccem: Coarsened  Exact Matching in Stata,\xe2\x80\x9d The Stata Journal, Vol. 9, No. 4 (2009): Pp. 524546.  Honaker, James and Gary King, \xe2\x80\x9cWhat to do About Missing Values in Time Series CrossSection Data,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 54, No. 2 (April, 2010): Pp.  561581.  Hopkins, Daniel and Gary King \xe2\x80\x9cImproving Anchoring Vignettes: Designing Surveys  to Correct Interpersonal Incomparability,\xe2\x80\x9d Public Opinion Quarterly, (2010): Pp. 1-22,  doi:10.1093/poq/nfq011.  Imai, Kosuke; Gary King; and Clayton Nall. \xe2\x80\x9cMatched Pairs and the Future of ClusterRandomized Experiments: A Rejoinder,\xe2\x80\x9d Statistical Science, Vol. 24, No. 1 (2009): Pp.  6472.  Hopkins, Daniel and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Method of Automated Nonparametric Content Analysis for Social Science,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 54, No. 1 (January  2010): Pp. 229247.  Stefano M. Iacus, Gary King, and Giuseppe Porro, \xe2\x80\x9cCEM: Software for Coarsened Exact  Matching,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software, Vol. 30, Issue 9 (June 2009).  Gutmann, Myron P.; Mark Abrahamson; Margaret O. Adams; Micah Altman; Caroline  Arms; Kenneth Bollen; Michael Carlson; Jonathan Crabtree; Darrell Donakowski; Gary  King; Jaret Lyle; Marc Maynard; Amy Pienta; Richard Rockwell; Lois Timms-Ferrara;  and Copeland H. Young. \xe2\x80\x9cFrom Preserving the Past to Preserving the Future: The DataPASS Project and the Challenges of Preserving Digital Social Science Data,\xe2\x80\x9d Library  Trends, Vol. 57, No. 3 (Winter, 2009): Pp. 315337.  King, Gary; Emmanuela Gakidou; Kosuke Imai; Jason Lakin; Ryan T. Moore; Clayton  Nall; Nirmala Ravishankar; Manett Vargas; Martha Mar\xc4\xb1\xcc\x81a Te\xcc\x81llez-Rojo; Juan Eugenio  Herna\xcc\x81ndez A\xcc\x81vila; Mauricio Herna\xcc\x81ndez A\xcc\x81vila; and He\xcc\x81ctor Herna\xcc\x81ndez Llamas. \xe2\x80\x9cPublic  Policy for the Poor? A Randomised Assessment of the Mexican Universal Health Insurance  Program,\xe2\x80\x9d The Lancet, Vol. 373 (25 April 2009): 14471454.  Lazer, David; Alex Pentland; Lada Adamic; Sinan Aral; Albert-La\xcc\x81szlo\xcc\x81 Baraba\xcc\x81si; Devon  Brewer; Nicholas Christakis; Noshir Contractor; James Fowler; Myron Gutmann; Tony  Jebara; Gary King; Michael Macy; Deb Roy; Marshall Van Alstyne, \xe2\x80\x9cComputational    Gary King    13    Social Science,\xe2\x80\x9d Science Vol. 323, No. 5915 (6 February 2009): Pp. 721723, copy at  http://j.mp/1AzJLs5.  Abrahamson, Mark; Kenneth A. Bollen; Myron Gutmann; Gary King; Amy M. Pienta  \xe2\x80\x9cPreserving Quantitative Research-Elicited Data for Longitudinal Analysis. New Developments in Archiving Survey Data in the U.S.,\xe2\x80\x9d Historical Social Research, Vol. 34, No. 3  (Summer, 2009): 5159, copy at http://j.mp/kiI2TH.  Imai, Kosuke; Gary King; and Clayton Nall. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Essential Role of Pair Matching in  Cluster-Randomized Experiments, with Application to the Mexican Universal Health Insurance Evaluation,\xe2\x80\x9d [with discussion], Statistical Science, Vol. 24, No. 1 (2009): Pp.  2953.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cEmpirical versus Theoretical Claims about Extreme  Counterfactuals: A Response,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 17 (2009): Pp. 107112. [a response  to a discussion of Gary King and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Dangers of Extreme Counterfactuals,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 14, No. 2 (2006): Pp. 131-159.]  Murray, Megan and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Effects of International Monetary Fund Loans  on Health Outcomes,\xe2\x80\x9d PLoS Medicine, Vol. 5, No. 7 (2008), e162. [Reprinted in Azmal  Hussain, ed., Addressing Health Challenges: The Role of International Agencies, ICFAI  University Press, April, 2009.]  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Changing Evidence Base of Social Science Research,\xe2\x80\x9d in Gary King,  Kay Schlozman, and Norman Nie, eds., The Future of Political Science: 100 Perspectives  New York: Routledge Press, 2009.  King, Gary; Kay Schlozman; and Norman Nie. \xe2\x80\x9cAn Introduction to the Future of Political  Science,\xe2\x80\x9d in Gary King, Kay Schlozman, and Norman Nie, eds., The Future of Political  Science: 100 Perspectives New York: Routledge Press, 2009.  Imai, Kosuke; Gary King; and Olivia Lau. \xe2\x80\x9cToward A Common Framework for Statistical  Analysis and Development,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics, Vol. 17,  No. 4 (2008): Pp. 892913.  King, Gary; Ori Rosen; Martin Tanner; and Alexander F. Wagner, \xe2\x80\x9cOrdinary Economic  Voting Behavior in the Extraordinary Election of Adolf Hitler,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Economic  History, Vol. 68, No. 4 (December, 2008): Pp. 951996.  Ho, Daniel; Kosuke Imai; Gary King; Elizabeth Stuart. \xe2\x80\x9cMatchIt: Nonparametric Preprocessing for Parametric Causal Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software, Vol. 42, No.  8 (2011).  King, Gary and Ying Lu. \xe2\x80\x9cVerbal Autopsy Methods with Multiple Causes,\xe2\x80\x9d Statistical  Science, Vol. 23, No. 1 (February, 2008), Pp. 7891.  Imai, Kosuke; Gary King; and Elizabeth Stuart, \xe2\x80\x9cMisunderstandings among Experimentalists and Observationalists about Causal Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of the Royal Statistical  Society, Series A, Vol. 171, Part 2 (2008): Pp. 1-22.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cAn Introduction to the Dataverse Network as an Infrastructure for Data  Sharing,\xe2\x80\x9d [with discussion] Sociological Methods and Research, Vol. 32, No. 2 (November,  2007): Pp. 173199.    Gary King    14    King, Gary; Emmanuela Gakidou; Nirmala Ravishankar; Ryan T. Moore; Jason Lakin;  Manett Vargas; Martha Mar\xc4\xb1\xcc\x81a Te\xcc\x81llez-Rojo; Juan Eugenio Herna\xcc\x81ndez A\xcc\x81vila; Mauricio  Herna\xcc\x81ndez A\xcc\x81vila; and He\xcc\x81ctor Herna\xcc\x81ndez Llamas. \xe2\x80\x9cA \xe2\x80\x98Politically Robust Experimental  Design for Public Policy Evaluation, with Application to the Mexican Universal Health  Insurance Program,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Policy Analysis and Management, Vol. 26, Issue 3 (2007):  Pp. 479506.  Altman, Micah and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Proposed Standard for the Scholarly Citation of  Quantitative Data,\xe2\x80\x9d D-Lib Magazine, Vol. 13, No. 3/4 (March/April, 2007).  Ho, Daniel E.; Kosuke Imai; Gary King; and Elizabeth Stuart. \xe2\x80\x9cMatching as Nonparametric Preprocessing for Reducing Model Dependence in Parametric Causal Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d  Political Analysis, Vol. 15 (2007): Pp. 199-236.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cDetecting Model Dependence in Statistical Inference: A  Response,\xe2\x80\x9d International Studies Quarterly, Vol. 51 (March, 2007): Pp. 231241.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cWhen Can History be Our Guide? The Pitfalls of Counterfactual Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d [with discussion] International Studies Quarterly, Vol. 51 (March,  2007): Pp. 183210.  Grofman, Bernard and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Future of Partisan Symmetry as a Judicial Test  for Partisan Gerrymandering after LULAC v. Perry,\xe2\x80\x9d Election Law Journal, Vol. 6, No.  1, (January, 2007), Pp. 235.  King, Gary and Jonathan Wand. \xe2\x80\x9cComparing Incomparable Survey Responses: New Tools  for Anchoring Vignettes,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 15, No. 1 (Winter, 2007): Pp. 4666.  King, Gary; Ori Rosen; and Martin Tanner. \xe2\x80\x9cEcological Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d in Larry Blume and  Steven N. Durlauf, eds., The New Palgrave Dictionary of Economics, 2nd edition, 2006.  Gakidou, Emmanuela and Gary King, \xe2\x80\x9cDeath by Survey: Estimating Adult Mortality  without Selection Bias from Sibling Survival Data\xe2\x80\x9d Demography, Vol. 43, No. 3 (August,  2006): Pp. 569585. [Reprinted in W. Paul Vogt, ed., Selecting Research Methods, London:  Sage Publications, 2008.]  Stoll, Heather; Gary King; and Langche Zeng, 2005. \xe2\x80\x9cWhatIf: Software for Evaluating Counterfactuals,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software, Vol. 15, Issue 4 (2005): Pp. 118,  abstract published in Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics, Vol. 15, No. 1  (March 2006): P. 264.  Epstein, Lee; Daniel E. Ho; Gary King; and Jeffrey A. Segal \xe2\x80\x9cThe Effect of War on the  Supreme Court,\xe2\x80\x9d in Samuel Kernell and Steven S. Smith, eds.(3rd ed). Principles and  Practice in American Politics: Classic and Contemporary Readings. Washington, D.C.:  Congressional Quarterly Press, 2006.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Dangers of Extreme Counterfactuals,\xe2\x80\x9d Political  Analysis, Vol. 14, No. 2 (2006): Pp. 131-159.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cPublication, Publication,\xe2\x80\x9d PS: Political Science and Politics, Vol. XXXIX,  No. 1 (January, 2006), 119125.    Gary King    15    Epstein, Lee; Daniel E. Ho; Gary King; and Jeffrey A. Segal, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Supreme Court During  Crisis: How War Affects only Non-War Cases,\xe2\x80\x9d New York University Law Review, Vol. 80,  No. 1 (April, 2005): 1-116.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cEI: A Program for Ecological Inference\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software, Vol.  11, Issue 7 (September, 2004): Pp. 141. Abstract published in Journal of Computational  and Graphical Statistics.  King, Gary; Ori Rosen; and Martin Tanner. \xe2\x80\x9cInformation in Ecological Inference: An  Introduction\xe2\x80\x9d in King, Rosen, and Tanner, eds., Ecological Inference: New Methodological  Strategies, New York: Cambridge University Press, 2004.  Imai, Kosuke and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cDid Illegally Counted Overseas Absentee Ballots Decide  the 2000 U.S. Presidential Election?,\xe2\x80\x9d Perspectives on Politics, Vol. 2, No. 3 (September,  2004): Pp. 537549.  Gill, Jeff and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cWhat to do When Your Hessian is Not Invertible: Alternatives  to Model Respecification in Nonlinear Estimation,\xe2\x80\x9d Sociological Methods and Research,  Vol. 33, No. 1 (2004): Pp. 5487.  Gill, Jeff and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cNumerical Issues Involved in Inverting Hessian Matrices,\xe2\x80\x9d  Pp. 143176 (Chapter 6) in Micah Altman, Jeff Gill, and Michael P. McDonald, eds.,  Numerical Issues in Statistical Computing for the Social Scientist, Hoboken, NJ: John  Wiley and Sons, Inc., 2003.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cFinding New Information for Ecological Inference Models: A Comment on  Jon Wakefield, \xe2\x80\x98Ecological Inference in 2 \xc3\x97 2 Tables,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of the Royal Statistical  Society, Series A, Vol. 167 (2004): P. 437.  Beck, Nathaniel; Gary King; and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cTheory and Evidence in International  Conflict: A Response to de Marchi, Gelpi, and Grynaviski,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science  Review, Vol. 98, No. 2 (May, 2004): Pp. 379389. [A response to a discussion of Nathaniel  Beck; Gary King; and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cImproving Quantitative Studies of International  Conflict: A Conjecture,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science Review, Vol. 94, No. 1 (March, 2000):  2136.]  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cInference in Case-Control Studies,\xe2\x80\x9d in Shein-Chung Chow,  ed., Encyclopedia of Biopharmaceutical Statistics, 2nd edition. New York: Marcel Dekker,  2004.  King, Gary; Christopher J.L. Murray; Joshua A. Salomon; and Ajay Tandon. \xe2\x80\x9cEnhancing the Validity and Cross-cultural Comparability of Measurement in Survey Research,\xe2\x80\x9d  American Political Science Review, Vol. 97, No. 4 (December, 2003), 567584; reprinted,  with printing errors corrected, Vol. 98, No. 1 (February, 2004): 191207. [Reprinted in:  (1) David J Bartholomew, ed., Measurement, Los Angeles: Sage Publications, 2006; (2)  Susanne Pickel, Gert Pickel, Hans-Joachim Lauth, and Detlef Jahn. 2007 Methoden der  vergleichenden Politikwissenschaft. Neuere Entwicklungen und Anwendungen (Methods of  Comparative Political Science. Latest Developments and Applications), Wiesbaden: VSVerlag; (3) W. Paul Vogt, ed., Selecting Research Methods, London: Sage Publications,  2008.]    Gary King    16    Gelman, Andrew; Jonathan Katz; and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cEmpirically Evaluating the Electoral  College,\xe2\x80\x9d Chapter 5, Pp. 7588, in Ann N. Crigler, Marion R. Just, and Edward J. McCaffery, eds., Rethinking the Vote: The Politics and Prospects of American Electoral Reform,  New York: Oxford University Press, 2004.  Epstein, Lee and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cBuilding An Infrastructure for Empirical Research in the  Law\xe2\x80\x9d [with comments from four law school deans], Journal of Legal Education, Vol. 53,  No. 311, (2003): Pp. 311320.  Lowe, Will and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cSome Statistical Methods for Evaluating Information Extraction Systems,\xe2\x80\x9d in K. Pastra, ed. Proceedings of the Workshop on Evaluation Initiatives in  Natural Language Processing. 10th Conference of the European Association for Computational Linguistics, Budapest, Hungary (2003): Pp. 1926.  King, Gary and Will Lowe. \xe2\x80\x9cAn Automated Information Extraction Tool For International  Conflict Data with Performance as Good as Human Coders: A Rare Events Evaluation  Design\xe2\x80\x9d International Organization, Vol. 57, No. 03 (July, 2003): pp. 617642.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Future of Replication,\xe2\x80\x9d International Studies Perspectives, Vol. 4, No.  1 (February, 2003): Pp. 100105. [in \xe2\x80\x9cSymposium on Replication in International Studies  Research,\xe2\x80\x9d following up on Gary King, \xe2\x80\x9cReplication, Replication\xe2\x80\x9d PS: Political Science  and Politics, Vol. XXVIII, No. 3 (September, 1995): Pp. 443499.]  Tomz, Michael; Gary King; and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cReLogit: Rare Events Logistic Regression,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software, Vol. 8, Issue 2 (2003): Pp. 127. Abstract published  in Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics, Vol. 12, No. 1 (March, 2003): 246  247.  Tomz, Michael; Jason Wittenberg; and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cCLARIFY: Software for Interpreting  and Presenting Statistical Results,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Statistical Software, Vol. 8, Issue 1 (2003):  Pp. 130. Abstract published in Journal of Computational and Graphical Statistics, Vol.  12, No. 1 (March, 2003): 245246.  Adolph, Christopher and Gary King, with Michael C. Herron and Kenneth W. Shotts. \xe2\x80\x9cA  Consensus on Second Stage Analyses in Ecological Inference Models,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis,  Vol. 11, No. 1 (Winter, 2003): Pp. 8694.  Adolph, Christopher and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cAnalyzing Second Stage Ecological Regressions,\xe2\x80\x9d  Political Analysis, Vol. 11, (Winter, 2003): Pp. 6576.  Gakidou, Emmanuela and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cMeasuring Total Health Inequality: Adding Individual Variation to Group-Level Differences\xe2\x80\x9d BioMed Central: International Journal for  Equity in Health, Vol. 1, No. 3 (2002). [Reprinted in Christopher Murray and David B.  Evans, eds., Health Systems Performance Assessment: Debates, Methods, and Empiricism,  Geneva: World Health Organization, 2003, Chapter 35, Pp. 485496.]  Gakidou, Emmanuela and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cDeterminants of Inequality in Child Survival:  Results from 39 Countries,\xe2\x80\x9d 2003, in Christopher Murray and David B. Evans, eds., Health  Systems Performance Assessment: Debates, Methods, and Empiricism, Geneva: World  Health Organization, Chapter 36, Pp. 497502.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cEstimating Risk and Rate Levels, Ratios, and Differences  in Case-Control Studies,\xe2\x80\x9d Statistics in Medicine, Vol. 21 (2002): Pp. 14091427.    Gary King    17    King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cIsolating Spatial Autocorrelation, Aggregation Bias, and Distributional Violations in Ecological Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 10, No. 3, (Summer, 2002): 298  300.  Murray, Christopher J.L.; Gary King; Alan D. Lopez; Niels Tomijima; and Etienne Krug,  \xe2\x80\x9cArmed Conflict as a Public Health Problem,\xe2\x80\x9d BMJ, Vol. 324, (9 February 2002): 346349.  (The BMJ was once called the British Medical Journal.)  King, Gary and Christopher J.L. Murray. \xe2\x80\x9cRethinking Human Security,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Science  Quarterly, Vol. 116, No. 4 (Winter, 2002): 585610.  Epstein, Lee and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Rules of Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d with comments from six scholars and a rejoinder by us, \xe2\x80\x9cEmpirical Research and The Goals of Legal Scholarship: A  Response,\xe2\x80\x9d University of Chicago Law Review, Vol. 69, No. 1 (Winter, 2002): Pp. 1209.  A Chinese translation is forthcoming in the Journal of Legal Methods, and a Portugese  translation in the Revista da Faculdade de Direito da UFRGS.  Honaker, James; Gary King; and Jonathan N. Katz. \xe2\x80\x9cA Fast, Easy, and Efficient Estimator  for Multiparty Electoral Data,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 10, No. 1, (Winter, 2002): 84100.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cImproving Forecasts of State Failure,\xe2\x80\x9d World Politics,  Vol. 53, No. 4 (July, 2001): 623-58.  Rosen, Ori and Wenxin Jiang, Gary King, and Martin A. Tanner, \xe2\x80\x9cBayesian and Frequentist Inference for Ecological Inference: The RxC Case,\xe2\x80\x9d Statistica Neerlandica, Vol. 55,  No. 2 (2001): Pp. 134156.  Altman, Micah; Leonid Andreev; Mark Diggory; Gary King; Daniel L. Kiskis; Elizabeth Kolster; M. Krot; and Sidney Verba. \xe2\x80\x9cA Digital Library for the Dissemination and  Replication of Quantitative Social Science Research: The Virtual Data Center,\xe2\x80\x9d in Social  Science Computer Review, Vol. 19, No. 4 (Winter, 2001): Pp. 458470.  Altman, Micah; Leonid Andreev; Mark Diggory; Gary King; Daniel L. Kiskis; Elizabeth  Kolster; M. Krot; and Sidney Verba. \xe2\x80\x9cAn Introduction to the Virtual Data Center Project  and Software,\xe2\x80\x9d in Proceedings of The First ACM+IEEE Joint Conference on Digital Libraries, ACM Press (2001): Pp. 203204.  King, Gary; James Honaker, Anne Joseph, and Kenneth Scheve. \xe2\x80\x9cAnalyzing Incomplete  Political Science Data: An Alternative Algorithm for Multiple Imputation,\xe2\x80\x9d American  Political Science Review, Vol. 95, No. 1 (March, 2001): Pp. 4969. [Reprinted in Martin  Bulmer, Patrick J Sturgis, and Nick Allum, eds., The Secondary Analysis of Survey Data,  Vol. 2, Sage Publications, 2009.] [Reprinted in Salvatore Babones, ed., Fundamentals of  Regression Modeling, Los Angeles: Sage Publications.]  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cLogistic Regression in Rare Events Data,\xe2\x80\x9d Political  Analysis, Vol. 9, No. 2 (Spring, 2001): Pp. 137163.  King, Gary and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cExplaining Rare Events in International Relations,\xe2\x80\x9d  International Organization, Vol. 55, No. 3 (Summer, 2001): Pp. 693715.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cProper Nouns and Methodological Propriety: Pooling Dyads in International Relations Data,\xe2\x80\x9d [concluding comment in a symposium on the analysis of dyadic    Gary King    18    international conflict data], International Organization, Vol. 55, No. 2 (Fall, 2001): Pp.  497507.  Alt, James E.; Gary King; and Curtis Signorino. \xe2\x80\x9cAggregation Among Binary, Count,  and Duration Models: Estimating the Same Quantities from Different Levels of Data,\xe2\x80\x9d  Political Analysis, Vol. 9, No. 1 (Winter, 2001): Pp. 2144.  Beck, Nathaniel; Gary King; and Langche Zeng. \xe2\x80\x9cImproving Quantitative Studies of  International Conflict: A Conjecture,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science Review, Vol. 94, No. 1  (March, 2000): 2136.  King, Gary; Michael Tomz; and Jason Wittenberg. \xe2\x80\x9cMaking the Most of Statistical Analyses: Improving Interpretation and Presentation,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science,  Vol. 44, No. 2 (April, 2000): 341355. (replication dataset: ICPSR 1255). [Reprinted in  Jacqueline Scott and Yu Xie, eds., Quantitative Social Science, Vol. 3, Sage Publications,  2005.]  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cGeography, Statistics, and Ecological Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d Annals of the Association  of American Geographers, Vol. 90, No. 3 (September, 2000): Pp. 601606.[Response to a  symposium on Gary King A Solution to the Ecological Inference Problem: Reconstructing  Individual Behavior from Aggregate Data, Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1997.]  Lewis, Jeffrey and Gary King, \xe2\x80\x9cNo Evidence on Directional vs. Proximity Voting,\xe2\x80\x9d Political  Analysis, Vol. 8, No. 1 (August, 1999): Pp. 2133.  Katz, Jonathan and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Statistical Model for Multiparty Electoral Data,\xe2\x80\x9d  American Political Science Review, Vol. 93, No. 1 (March, 1999): 15-32 (replication  dataset: ICPSR 1190).  King, Gary; Ori Rosen; and Martin Tanner. \xe2\x80\x9cBinomial-Beta Hierarchical Models for  Ecological Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d Sociological Methods and Research, Vol. 28, No. 1 (August, 1999):  6190.  King, Gary, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Future of Ecological Inference Research: A Reply to Freedman et al.,\xe2\x80\x9d  Journal of the American Statistical Association, March, 1999.  King, Gary and Bradley Palmquist, \xe2\x80\x9cThe Record of American Democracy, 19841990,\xe2\x80\x9d  Sociological Methods and Research, Vol. 26, No. 3 (February, 1998): 424427; and PS:  Political Science and Politics, Vol. XXX, No. 4 (December, 1997): 746747; and ICPSR  Bulletin, Vol. XVIII, No. 4 (May, 1998): 13.  Gelman, Andrew; Gary King; and Chuanhai Liu. \xe2\x80\x9cNot Asked and Not Answered: Multiple  Imputation for Multiple Surveys,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of the American Statistical Association, Vol.  93, No. 443 (September, 1999): Pp. 846857. \xe2\x80\x9cRejoinder,\xe2\x80\x9d Pp. 869874  King, Gary and Michael Laver. \xe2\x80\x9cMany Publications, but Still No Evidence,\xe2\x80\x9d Electoral  Studies, Vol. 18, No. 4, (December, 1999): Pp. 597598.  Gelman, Andrew; Gary King; and John Boscardin. \xe2\x80\x9cEstimating the Probability of Events  that Have Never Occurred: When Is Your Vote Decisive?\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of the American  Statistical Association, Vol. 93, No. 441 (March, 1998): Pp. 19.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cWhy Context Should Not Count,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Geography Vol. 15, No. 2 (February, 1996): Pp. 159164.    Gary King    19    Benoit, Kenneth and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Preview of EI and EzI: Programs for Ecological  Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d Social Science Computer Review, Vol. 14, No. 4 (Winter, 1996): Pp. 433438.  Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cAdvantages of Conflictual Redistricting,\xe2\x80\x9d Pp. 207218  in Iain McLean and David Butler, eds., Fixing the Boundary: Defining and Redefining  Single-Member Electoral Districts, Aldershot, England: Dartmouth Publishing Company,  1996.  King, Gary; John Bruce; and Andrew Gelman. \xe2\x80\x9cRacial Fairness in Legislative Redistricting,\xe2\x80\x9d in Paul E. Peterson, ed., Classifying by Race, Princeton: Princeton University Press,  1996.  King, Gary and Curtis S. Signorino. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Generalization in the Generalized Event Count  Model, With Comments on Achen, Amato, and Londregan,\xe2\x80\x9d [a response to three authors  in a symposium on \xe2\x80\x9cGary Kings Generalized Event Count Model\xe2\x80\x9d] Political Analysis, Vol.  6 (1996): Pp. 225252.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cReplication, Replication,\xe2\x80\x9d PS: Political Science and Politics, with comments  from nineteen authors and a response, \xe2\x80\x9cA Revised Proposal, Proposal,\xe2\x80\x9d Vol. XXVIII, No.  3 (September, 1995): Pp. 443499. [Reprinted in Martin Bulmer, Patrick J Sturgis, and  Nick Allum, eds., The Secondary Analysis of Survey Data, Vol. 1, Sage Publications, 2009.]  King, Gary; Robert O. Keohane; and Sidney Verba. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Importance of Research Design in Political Science,\xe2\x80\x9d a response to five authors in the symposium \xe2\x80\x9cThe QualitativeQuantitative Disputation: Gary King, Robert O. Keohane, and Sidney Verbas Designing  Social Inquiry: Scientific Inference in Qualitiative Research\xe2\x80\x9d, in American Political Science Review, Vol. 89, No. 2 (June, 1995): Pp. 454481  Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cEnhancing Democracy Through Legislative Redistricting,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science Review, Vol. 88, No. 3 (September, 1994): Pp. 541559,  (replication dataset: ICPSR s1101). [Parts reprinted in California Policy Studies Brief, a  publication of the California Policy Seminar, Vol. 7, No. 5 (April, 1995).]  Voss, D. Steven; Andrew Gelman; and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cPre-Election Survey Methodology:  Details From Nine Polling Organizations, 1988 and 1992,\xe2\x80\x9d Public Opinion Quarterly, Vol.  59 (1995): Pp. 98132.  Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Unified Method of Evaluating Electoral Systems and  Redistricting Plans,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 38, No. 2 (May, 1994):  Pp. 514554, (replication dataset: ICPSR s1054).  Alt, James E. and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cTransfers of Governmental Power: The Meaning of Time  Dependence,\xe2\x80\x9d Comparative Political Studies, Vol. 27, No. 2 (July, 1994): Pp. 190210.  (dataset: ICPSR s1115).  Winkelmann, Rainer; Curtis Signorino; and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cA Correction for an Underdispersed Event Count Probability Distribution,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, (1995): Pp. 215228.  Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cParty Competition and Media Messages in U.S. Presidential Election Campaigns,\xe2\x80\x9d in L. Sandy Maisel, ed., The Parties Respond: Changes in  the American Party System, 2nd edition, Boulder, Colorado: Westview Press, 1994, Pp.  255-295.    Gary King    20    Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cWhy Are American Presidential Election Campaign  Polls So Variable When Votes are So Predictable?\xe2\x80\x9d British Journal of Political Science,  Vol. 23, No. 1 (October, 1993): Pp. 409451. [Reprinted in (1) Philip Seib, ed., Political  Communication, Vol. 3, Sage Publications, 2007, and (2) Kai Arzheimer and Jocelyn  Evans, eds., Electoral Behaviour, Vol. 3, Sage Publications, 2008.]  King, Gary; John M. Bruce; and Michael Gilligan. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Science of Political Science  Graduate Admissions,\xe2\x80\x9d PS: Political Science and Politics, Vol. XXVI, No. 4, (December,  1993): Pp. 772778.  King, Gary and Michael Laver. \xe2\x80\x9cOn Party Platforms, Mandates, and Government Spending,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science Review, Vol. 87, No. 3 (September, 1993): Pp. 744750,  (replication dataset: ICPSR s1109).  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cThe Methodology of Presidential Research,\xe2\x80\x9d in George Edwards, III, John  H. Kessel, and Bert A. Rockman, eds., Researching the Presidency: Vital Questions, New  Approaches, Pittsburgh: University of Pittsburgh, 1993: Pp. 387412.  King, Gary and Daniel J. Walsh. \xe2\x80\x9cGood Research and Bad Research: Extending Zimiles  Criticism,\xe2\x80\x9d Early Childhood Research Quarterly, Vol. 8, No. 3 (September, 1993): Pp.  397401.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9c \xe2\x80\x98Truth is Stranger than Prediction, More Questionable Than Causal Inference,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 35, No. 4 (November, 1991): Pp.  10471053. [A response to a discussion of Gary King \xe2\x80\x9cHow Not to Lie With Statistics:  Avoiding Common Mistakes in Quantitative Political Science,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 30, No. 3 (August, 1986): Pp. 666687.]  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cConstituency Service and Incumbency Advantage,\xe2\x80\x9d British Journal of Political Science, Vol. 21, No. 1 (January, 1991): Pp. 119128, (replication dataset: ICPSR  s1108).  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cOn Political Methodology,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 2 (1991): Pp. 130.  (replication dataset: ICPSR s1053).  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cStochastic Variation: A Comment on Lewis-Beck and Skalabans \xe2\x80\x98The RSquare,\xe2\x80\x9d Political Analysis, Vol. 2 (1991): Pp. 185200. [A response to a discussion of  Gary King \xe2\x80\x9cHow Not to Lie With Statistics: Avoiding Common Mistakes in Quantitative  Political Science,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 30, No. 3 (August, 1986):  Pp. 666687.]  King, Gary and Andrew Gelman. \xe2\x80\x9cSystemic Consequences of Incumbency Advantage in  the U.S. House,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 35, No. 1 (February, 1991):  Pp. 110138, (dataset: ICPSR 06311).  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cCalculating Standard Errors of Predicted Values based on Nonlinear Functional Forms,\xe2\x80\x9d The Political Methodologist, Vol. 4, No. 2 (Fall, 1991).  Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cEstimating Incumbency Advantage Without Bias,\xe2\x80\x9d  American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 34, No. 4 (November, 1990): Pp. 11421164,  (dataset: ICPSR 06311).  King, Gary; James Alt; Nancy Burns; and Michael Laver. \xe2\x80\x9cA Unified Model of Cabinet  Dissolution in Parliamentary Democracies,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol.    Gary King    21    34, No. 3 (August, 1990): Pp. 846871; Errata Vol. 34, No. 4 (November, 1990): P. 1168.  (replication dataset: ICPSR s1115).  Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cEstimating the Electoral Consequences of Legislative  Redistricting,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of the American Statistical Association, Vol. 85, No. 410 (June,  1990): Pp. 274282.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cElectoral Responsiveness and Partisan Bias in Multiparty Democracies,\xe2\x80\x9d  Legislative Studies Quarterly, Vol. XV, No. 2 (May, 1990): Pp. 159181.  Ansolabehere, Stephen and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cMeasuring the Consequences of Delegate Selection Rules in Presidential Nominations,\xe2\x80\x9d Journal of Politics, Vol. 52, No. 2 (May, 1990):  Pp. 609621.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cRepresentation Through Legislative Redistricting: A Stochastic Model,\xe2\x80\x9d  American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 33, No. 4 (November, 1989): Pp. 787824.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cEvent Count Models for International Relations: Generalizations and Applications,\xe2\x80\x9d International Studies Quarterly, Vol. 33, No. 2 (June, 1989): Pp. 123147.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cVariance Specification in Event Count Models: From Restrictive Assumptions to a Generalized Estimator,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 33, No. 3  (August, 1989): Pp. 762784.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cA Seemingly Unrelated Poisson Regression Model,\xe2\x80\x9d Sociological Methods  and Research, Vol. 17, No. 3 (February, 1989): Pp. 235255.  Gelman, Andrew and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cElectoral Responsiveness in U.S. Congressional Elections, 19461986,\xe2\x80\x9d abstract, Proceedings of the Social Statistics Section, American Statistical Association, 1989: P. 208.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cStatistical Models for Political Science Event Counts: Bias in Conventional  Procedures and Evidence for The Exponential Poisson Regression Model,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 32, No. 3 (August, 1988): Pp. 838863.  King, Gary and Robert X Browning. \xe2\x80\x9cDemocratic Representation and Partisan Bias in  Congressional Elections,\xe2\x80\x9d American Political Science Review, Vol. 81, No. 4 (December,  1987): 12521273.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cPresidential Appointments to the Supreme Court: Adding Systematic Explanation to Probabilistic Description,\xe2\x80\x9d American Politics Quarterly, Vol. 15, No. 3 (July,  1987): Pp. 373386.  Browning, Robert X and Gary King. \xe2\x80\x9cSeats, Votes, and Gerrymandering: Measuring  Bias and Representation in Legislative Redistricting\xe2\x80\x9d Law and Policy, Vol. 9, No. 3 (July,  1987): Pp. 305322.  King, Gary. \xe2\x80\x9cHow Not to Lie With Statistics: Avoiding Common Mistakes in Quantitative  Political Science,\xe2\x80\x9d American Journal of Political Science, Vol. 30, No. 3 (August, 1986):  Pp. 666687"
</cv>
