<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cv>
"College of Computing  &amp; <label type="Job Specific Skills">Digital Media  Entry</label>-Level  Resume Guide    This packet is intended to serve as a starting point for creating or improving your resume.  It includes sample resumes, as well as best practices and helpful resources for developing a  successful document.  DePaul Universitys Peer Career Advisors are available on a walk-in basis to assist you with  creating and/or improving your resume. Inquire about Peer Career Advisor Program hours  by calling the Career Center at (123)345-7890 (Loop Campus) or (123)345-7890 (Lincoln  Park Campus).    Contents  I.    Resume Purpose, Design, &amp; Mechanics\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6..\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6..Page 3    II.    Key Elements of a Successful Resumes\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6.\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6....Page 4  This document is intended to guide you in creating your resume by outlining  important types of information to include and tips for doing so in a professional and  persuasive manner. Please note this is not intended as a template and the format  employed may or may not best represent you. Consider meeting with a Peer Career  Advisor to discuss how you might best layout your own resume.    III.    Transferable Skills &amp; Action Verbs\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6.Page 5  Transferable skills are those that can be applied in a variety of industries and job  functions. Considering which transferable skills you want to convey to employers is a  great place to start when composing your resume. This list is a sampling of the types of  skills you might highlight on your resume, in addition to those skills that are more  specific to your major, intended industry, or job function.  A sampling of action verbs is also included on this page. Be sure to use strong action  verbs to begin each of your bulleted statements, previewing the skill to be exemplified  through the accomplishment statement.    IV.    Chronological Resume Samples...\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6...Pages 6-11  In this most commonly accepted resume format, job titles and employers are  emphasized, starting with your most recent experiences to illustrate a progressive work  history. Your skills and accomplishments are described through bulleted statements  under each position. This resume type is recommended for people who have recently  graduated with a bachelors degree, those who are staying within the same career field,  and candidates with few time gaps in their job history. This type is most often preferred  by employers because it is easy to scan, highlights job titles, employers, and dates, and  clearly ties candidates skills and accomplishments to their work histories.    V.    Functional &amp; Combination Resume Samples...\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6..Pages 12-13  This format is an option for candidates who have changed employers frequently,  have gaps in their employment history, or are hoping to transition to a new industry  or unrelated job function. Functional resumes enable candidates to highlight  transferable skills, placing less emphasis on employment dates, job titles, and  employers.    VI.    Additional Career Center Resume Resources\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\xa6...Page 14    2    I. Resume Purpose, Design, &amp; Mechanics  The purpose of a resume is to market yourself to employers by succinctly summarizing your education, experience,  and skills, ultimately aiming to convince employers to invite you to interview. When conceptualizing your resume,  think of it as a marketing tool, rather than a simple work history, as it is intended to promote you as the perfect  candidate for the opportunity at hand.  Resume writing is an art, not a science. There is no one correct way to formulate a resume, but there are some best  practices and standards that the Career Center recommends. Stand out from the crowd with high quality content  and a clearly written, error-free document. Sequence the information from most important to least important with  regard to your career objective. When constructing bullet points, aim to highlight accomplishments that exemplify  the skills you possess and employers are seeking.  \xef\x81\xb6 Length: With a few rare exceptions, when applying for internships or entry-level jobs, students should  keep their resume to 1 page. If you have difficulty narrowing down your resume, consider removing  elements that are not closely related to the opportunities for which you are applying.  \xef\x81\xb6 Margins: Make your resume visually attractive. Use some whitespace to allow the readers eye to rest.  Using .5 inch to 1.5 inch margins is recommended.  \xef\x81\xb6 Font: Use a font that is easy to read. Times New Roman, Arial, and Courier New are good choices. A  10-12 point font size is recommended.  \xef\x81\xb6 Consistency: Keep the formatting consistent throughout your resume. For example, if you choose to bold  a job title, make sure you bold every job title. Also, make sure that all of your bullet points, section headers,  dates, etc. line up neatly on the page.  \xef\x81\xb6 Accuracy: Your resume, and all other job search materials, must be 100% error free. Be sure to carefully  read through your resume, checking grammar, spelling, and punctuation. It is a good idea to have at least  2-3 people proofread it as well.  \xef\x81\xb6 Be Accomplishment-Orientated: Employers hire you for your skills and want to read about times when  you have successfully utilized the skills they are seeking. Describe achievements, rather than listing duties,  quantify outcomes whenever possible, and be sure to highlight your proficiency in both technical (industry  or job function-specific) and transferable skills.  \xef\x81\xb6 Use Action Verbs: Strengthen your bullet points by beginning each with an action verb that previews the  skill to be exemplified in that accomplishment statement. This allows a potential employer to more easily  scan your resume for what he or she is seeking.  \xef\x81\xb6 Make it Clear and Be Succinct: Eliminate the pronoun \xe2\x80\x9cI\xe2\x80\x9d at the beginning of each bullet point as this is  assumed. Avoid introductory and wind-up phrases such as \xe2\x80\x9cMy duties included...\xe2\x80\x9d and \xe2\x80\x9cMy responsibilities  were\xe2\x80\xa6\xe2\x80\x9d  \xef\x81\xb6 Overall Appearance: Ask yourself and others if your document is easy to read and professional looking.  Also, consider that the average recruiter may scan your resume for 30 seconds or less. Make sure that your  most important information stands out.    3    II. Key Elements of a Successful Resume  Your First and Last Name  \xe2\x99\xa6 Phone number \xe2\x99\xa6 Email address \xe2\x99\xa6 Street address \xe2\x99\xa6 City, state &amp; zip code \xe2\x99\xa6  _______________________________________________________________________________________________________  OBJECTIVE  Create a statement describing or naming the position you are seeking to obtain. You may also include the specific field or area  you are interested in and the skills and expertise you could contribute to the company. This section is optional and could be  omitted or substituted with a \xe2\x80\x95Career Highlights\xe2\x80\x96 or \xe2\x80\x95Summary of Qualifications\xe2\x80\x96 section.  _______________________________________________________________________________________________________  EDUCATION  Institution City, State  (Expected) Graduation Month Year  Write out the full name of your (expected) degree; also list Minors and Concentrations  GPA: 4.0/4.0 (it is recommended that you include your GPA if it is 3.0 or higher)  Other possible information to include: Study Abroad experiences, Relevant Coursework, or Academic Awards and Honors.  _______________________________________________________________________________________________________  TECHNICAL SKILLS   Utilities   Languages   Software   Databases   Hardware  _____________________________________________________________________________________________________  EXPERIENCE, RELEVANT EXPERIENCE, INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE [possible titles/descriptive headings]  Organization, Your Job Title  City, State  Month Year - Month Year   The position header above is one example of formatting. Other formats can include using two lines or rearranging the order of  the Organization, Job Title, Location, and Dates to emphasize the most important elements.   You can bold or italicize your title or your organization\xe2\x80\x94whichever is more relevant, but be consistent.   In this section include bulleted accomplishment statements, which provide examples of times you have successfully used the  skills employers are seeking.   Start with a strong action verb, then follow with an explanation of what you were doing, describe how you did it, and, when  possible, include any outcomes that you achieved. Remember, statements should ultimately convey your proficiency in one or  more skill sets of interest to the employer by way of providing an example of when you have used them.   Consider the following questions to help you create more effective bullet points: What was the result/outcome of your work?  What were your accomplishments? How did you help the organization? What skills/knowledge did you enhance? How does  this experience relate to your internship/employment goal?  Organization, Your Job Title  City, State  Month Year - Month Year   Bulleted statements should be in the proper tense (past or present tense) and use consistent grammar and punctuation.   Be specific by including quantity, frequency, population, and impact of your work whenever possible.   Make sure your resume is easy to read and not too text heavy. Avoid using colors, multiple fonts, pictures, being too brief, or  making it too dense. Make it your own, but be professional.  _______________________________________________________________________________________________________  ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE, LEADERSHIP, HONORS, ACTIVITIES, COMMUNITY SERVICE, VOLUNTEER,  PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT [possible titles/descriptive headings]  Organization, Your Job Title  City, State  Month Year - Month Year   Using multiple experience sections is optional and allows you to emphasize (by placing it closer to the top) your most relevant  experience. Experiences within a section should be listed in reverse chronological order.   Positions within this section should be formatted like previous experience sections, but may or may not include bullet points.   In an additional experience section, you can include work experiences that may not be directly related to the job you are  applying to, but add to your credibility by exemplifying a progressive work history.   Emphasize your transferable skills, those that can be taken from one experience and applied elsewhere.  Organization, Your Role (e.g. Member, Participant, Honoree, or Presenter)  City, State Month Year - Month Year   This section can also be an opportunity to share your experiences as a leader, honors received, community involvement,  professional development activities, or membership in organizations. As illustrated, replace \xe2\x80\x95job title\xe2\x80\x96 with the role you played.    4    III. Transferable Skills &amp; Action Verbs  TRANSFERABLE SKILLS  Transferable skills are those that can be applied in multiple work settings. Consider incorporating them, in addition to those  that are specific to your intended career field, by providing examples of when you have successfully used them in your bulleted accomplishment statements. Some examples of transferable skills include the following:  CLERICAL  Bookkeeping  Classifying  Collecting  Compiling  Computing  Examining  Filing  Organizing  Recording  Word processing    PROBLEM SOLVING  Analyzing  Appraising  Diagnosing  Examining  Executing  Planning  Proving  Reasoning  Recognizing  Validating    TECHNICAL  Adjusting  Aligning  Assembling  Drafting  Engineering  Installing  Observing  Operating  Programming  Repairing    CREATIVE  Designing  Developing  Establishing  Illustrating  Imagining  Improvising  Inventing  performing  Revitalizing  Visualizing    RESEARCH  Assessing  Calculating  Collecting  Diagnosing  Evaluating  Examining  Extrapolating  Interviewing  Investigating  Synthesizing    TRAINING  Adapting  Communicating  Demonstrating  Enabling  Encouraging  Evaluating  Explaining  Instructing  Planning  Stimulating    ACTION VERBS  Beginning each bulleted accomplishment statement with a strong action verb helps to highlight your successes and allows a  reader to get a sense of your skills by scanning the page prior to reading each individual bullet point. It is a good idea to vary  the action verbs on your resume in order to appeal to different audiences. Below is a list of verbs to help get you started.  A  Achieved  Acted  Adapted  Adjusted  Administered  Advanced  Advised  Altered  Analyzed  Appraised  Arranged  Assembled  Assessed  Audited  B  Balanced  Budgeted  Built  C  Calculated  Calibrated  Categorized  Charted  Classified  Coached  Collected  Combined  Communicated  Compiled  Composed  Computed  Conducted  Configured  Consolidated  Constructed    Consulted  Contrasted  Controlled  Converted  Convinced  Coordinated  Counseled  Counted  Created  Cultivated  D  Decided  Decreased  Defined  Delivered  Demonstrated  Designed  Detected  Determined  Developed  Devised  Diagnosed  Differentiated  Distributed  Documented  Doubled  Drafted  E  Edited  Eliminated  Encouraged  Engineered  Enhanced  Ensured  Established  Estimated    Evaluated  Examined  Executed  Expanded  Expedited  F  Facilitated  Filed  Filled  Forecasted  Formulated  Fostered  Fulfilled  G  Gained  Gathered  Generated  Grew  Guided  H  Handled  Headed  Hired  I  Identified  Illustrated  Implemented  Improved  Increased  Influenced  Informed  Initiated  Inspected  Installed  Instituted  Instructed    Integrated  Intended  Interviewed  invented  Investigated  L  Launched  Lectured  Led  Liaised  Logged  M  Maintained  Managed  Manufactured  Marketed  Measured  Mediated  Mentored  Migrated  Minimized  Monitored  Motivated  N  Negotiated  O  Obtained  Operated  Orchestrated  Ordered  Organized  Originated  Oversaw  P  Performed  Persuaded    Planned  Posted  Prepared  Prescribed  Presented  Priced  Processed  Produced  Promoted  Proposed  Protected  Provided  Purchased  R  Realized  Received  Recommended  Reconciled  Recorded  Recruited  Redesigned  Reduced  Referred  Removed  Reorganized  Repaired  Reported  Represented  Researched  Resolved  Restructured  Revamped  Reviewed  Revised  Revitalized  Routed    S  Scheduled  Selected  Separated  Served  Serviced  Set up  Simplified  Sold  Solved  Specified  Started  Strategized  Streamlined  Strengthened  Studied  Summarized  Supervised  Supplied  Supported  T  Tested  Tracked  Trained  Transformed  Translated  Troubleshot  U  Updated  Upgraded  V  Verified  W  Weighed  Wired  Won    5    Sample 1: Chronological Resume  Student w/work Experience - Seeking Internship or Part Time work related to their major    Cara Nowak  252 N. Lincoln Ave  Chicago IL, 60657  123-345-7890  nowakc@gmail.com    Career Objective  To obtain an internship or part-time position in Information Systems or a related field utilizing  academic background and technical skills    Education  DePaul University, Chicago, IL  Bachelor of Science in Information Systems    June 2014  GPA: 3.6/4.0    Relevant Coursework  Intro to Desktop Databases  Database Design  Analysis and Design Techniques    Applied Networks and Security  Software Project Management  Content Management Systems    Technical Skills  Operating Systems:  Database Management:  Applications:  Languages:  Social Media:    Windows XP, 7  Oracle  MS Visio, MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)  HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, SQL  Twitter, Facebook    Work History  LEVIS, Seasonal Sales Associate, Chicago IL (Nov 2011  Jan 2012)   Greeted customers and to maintain the stores highest customer service rating in the district.   Assisted customers with finding merchandise and specialty items depending on specific needs.   Achieved seasonal sales goals by promoting new items and attracting new customers.  BORDERS, Seasonal Integrated Product Team Member, Gurnee IL (Oct 2009  Jan 2010)   Assisted with inventory management as member of operational team   Directed customers to merchandise based on their needs and kept consistent track of store  inventory  6    SAMPLE 2: Combination Resume  (Student w/ part-time work experience - Seeking Internship)    Arnav Malik  (123)345-7890    Arvav.malik91@gmail.com    EDUCATION  DePaul University, Chicago Illinois  Bachelor of Science in Interactive Media    Expected June 2013  3.3/4.0 G.P.A    Relevant Coursework: User Centered Evaluation, User Centered Web Design, Scripting for Interactive Media,  Advanced Scripting for Interactive Media, Intro to Human Computer Interaction, Virtual Worlds &amp; Online  Communities.  COURSE PROJECTS  User Centered Evaluation  Winter 2012   Interviews, Personas and Scenarios- Created and conducted interviews. Discovered information  regarding users, created user personas based off interviews, and created task scenarios from interviews.   Heuristic Evaluation and Cognitive Walkthrough- Performed a Heuristic Evaluation on an application  and developed tasks for and performed a Cognitive Walkthrough.   Preparation for Usability Testing- Learned steps for planning a Usability Test by creating problem statements, test objectives, a test design and a test script.   Usability Testing and Reporting- Conducted Usability Testing with an application and several participants. Used data to create a report of the tests findings.  Advanced Scripting for Interactive Media  Winter 2012   Application in Flash- Created an application in Flash using Object Oriented principles and implicated  XML into Flash ActionScript file.  EMPLOYMENT HISTORY  DePaul University, Chicago IL  Sept 2011-Present  DePaul Information Services  Classroom/Lab Technician   Provide customer relations and emergency technical support to DePaul University Faculty and Students.   Maintain printers, diagnose computer issues and provide computer support.  COMPUTER SKILLS  Word  HTML5  ActionScript    PowerPoint  CSS/CSS3  Adobe Photoshop    Excel  Adobe Flash  Adobe After Effects    7    SAMPLE 3: Chronological Resume  (Student w/ part-time &amp; internship experience - Seeking Entry Level position)    Douglas Noth  Dougnoth.23@gmail.com (123)345-7890  www.DougNothPortfolio.com  CAREER HIGHLIGHTS  \xef\x82\xa7  \xef\x82\xa7  \xef\x82\xa7  \xef\x82\xa7    2 years of experience in producing, directing, and editing videos, specifically documentaries  Completed the Atlantis Dual Degree Study Abroad Program in France and Sweden  Over 8 years of experience in community service, including fundraising, event and advocacy planning  Proven skills in organizing, implementing, and working with diverse team members    EDUCATION  Atlantis Dual Degree Study Abroad Program, June 2012  B. A. in Digital Cinema, DePaul University, Chicago, IL  B. A. in Business Administration, Linkoping University, Linkoping, Sweden  RELEVANT EXPERIENCE  Director/Producer: Atlantis Documentary, Chicago, IL, January 2012-Present  \xef\x82\xa7 Produce and direct a documentary on the Atlantis Study Abroad Program to promote dual degree programs  through DePaul and affiliate universities abroad.  \xef\x82\xa7 Travel to France and Sweden to coordinate and conduct interviews with University Presidents, Directors and  students.  Co-Producer/Camera Operator: Rafiki Collaborative Documentary, Kenya/ Chicago, IL, November 2010-Present  \xef\x82\xa7 Traveled to Kenya to film a 15-minute documentary, which portrayed cultural and structural issues surrounding  HIV and AIDS.  \xef\x82\xa7 Developed interviewing skills by conducting 11 interviews with local community leaders.  Assistant to Producer (Internship): Richter Studios, Chicago, IL, September 2010-December 2010  \xef\x82\xa7 Assisted Producer with various pre-production activities, including location scouting and shoot planning.  Co-Director/Co-Producer: Voices Documentary, Chicago, IL, January 2009-June 2009  \xef\x82\xa7 Commissioned by DePaul Community Service Organization to create a 20-minute documentary about social  justice on campus to be shown to all incoming freshman and elsewhere on campus to encourage student  involvement.  Featured Extra: Universal Studios, Chicago, IL, May 2008  \xef\x82\xa7 Worked as a paid extra on a Dennis Quaid film, The Express, for Universal Studios.  ACADEMIC PROJECTS  Sound Director: Cheap Seats movie for Project Bluelight, Chicago, IL, August 2009  \xef\x82\xa7 Directed sound for 30-minute short written and directed by a faculty member with a crew of 20 students.  Producer: Ride music video, Chicago, IL, July 2009  \xef\x82\xa7 Produced a 3-minute music video for local hip-hop artist and DJ with crew of 4 students.  OTHER EXPERIENCE  DePaul Community Service Association: Senior Team, Chicago, IL, August 2009-Current  Ole Lounge: Bartender/ Server, Chicago, IL, August 2008-January 2009  DePaul University: Resident Advisor, Chicago, IL, June 2010-August 2010  COMMUNITY SERVICE AND HONORS  Best Buddies E-Buddy, May 2007-July 2008  DePaul Community Service Coordinator, April 2009-March 2010  DePaul AIDS Project Volunteer, January 2009-2010  Special Olympics Volunteer, May 2008    8    SAMPLE 4: Chronological Resume  (Student in Masters program - Seeking Internship or Entry Level position)    Sam Elmudesi  samelmudesi@gmail.com  123-345-7890  linkedin.com/SamElmudesi  OBJECTIVE  Seeking to apply my education, technical skills and experience to an information security internship or  entry-level role.  EDUCATION  DePaul University, Chicago, IL  Master of Science in Computer, Information and Network Security  Network Security Concentration  Related Coursework:  Network Security  Information Security Management  Protocols &amp; Techniques for Data Networks  Legal Issues in Information Assurance  DePaul University, Chicago, IL  Bachelor of Science in Computer Science    June 2013  GPA 3.4/4.0    Computer Networks and Data Systems  Advanced Network Technologies &amp; Design  Advanced Network Defense Systems  Software Security Architecture  June 2011  GPA 3.6/4.0    TECHNICAL SKILLS  Operating Systems:  Networking:  Software:  Databases:  Languages:    UNIX (Red Hat), Linux (Ubuntu), Windows 7, XP  IPv4, IPv6, TCP/IP, LANs, WANs, VPNs, Routers, Switches, Firewalls  Wireshark, Splunk, Nessus, PatchLink, Nmap, Putty, Active Directory,  VMware, MS Office, MS Visio  Access, MySQL, Oracle  C++, C, Ruby on Rails, CSS, HTML, UML, Java, JavaScript, Perl, XML,  XHTML, Visual Basic, Python    RELATED EXPERIENCE  DePaul University, Chicago, IL  Sept 2012 Present  Help Desk Associate   Act as first point of contact for DePauls technology department. Assist faculty and students experiencing computer system issues in the classroom or computer lab.   Resolve issues in a timely and professional manner. Troubleshoot user account issues and reset  passwords.   Configure printers and upload new software in classroom computers or for faculty.  ACTIVITIES  DePaul University Security Daemons Member  DePaul University Computer Science Society\xe2\x80\x94Member    2012 Present  2011\xe2\x80\x94Present    9    SAMPLE 5: Chronological Resume  (Student w/Internship Experience - Seeking Entry-Level Position)    Hector Gonzales  123 Software Way  123-345-7890  Chicago, IL 60000  hgonzales@email.com  __________________________________________________________________________________________________________    OBJECTIVE: To obtain an internship or entry-level position where I can contribute 1+ years of IT experience and  education, as well as my collaboration and communication skills.  EDUCATION:  Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, DePaul University, Chicago, IL  Cumulative GPA: 3.0/4.0; Major GPA: 3.6/4.0    Expected June 2013    TECHNICAL SUMMARY:  Languages: SQL, PL/SQL, Java, JDBC, HTML, Visual Basic, Python, C++, C, XHTML  Software: SQL Developer, Net Beans, Eclipse, MS Office, MS Visio, Front Page, Adobe Photoshop  Operating Systems: Windows XP, Windows 7, UNIX  Databases: Oracle, MS Access, SQL  COURSE PROJECTS:  System Analysis and Design  Winter 2012  Production Control Project  \xef\x82\xa7 Led a team of five students in designing, coding and implementing an SQL database.  \xef\x82\xa7 Entered and updated information using a search engine robot.  \xef\x82\xa7 Completed analysis and designed documentation with data flow diagrams, structure charts, process  specifications, data-dictionary and a user manual.  E-Commerce  Summer 2012  Website Design Project  \xef\x82\xa7 Designed a personal web site using HTML; viewable at www.hgonzales1.depaul.edu.  RELATED EXPERIENCE:  Digiworld, Chicago, IL  May 2011  Present  Database Intern  \xef\x82\xa7 Maintain 1000 customer records in companys Access database.  \xef\x82\xa7 Update website with information on new events and services utilizing Front Page.  \xef\x82\xa7 Process online subscriptions, activating new subscriber accounts by creating usernames and passwords.  DePaul University, Chicago, IL  October 2010  May 2011  Lab Assistant  \xef\x82\xa7 Provided technical support to students in a lab with 150 workstations.  \xef\x82\xa7 Performed troubleshooting and problem-solving of hardware and software issues.  ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE:  General Office Company, Naperville, IL  Clerk  \xef\x82\xa7 Coordinated scheduling of events and meetings for multiple departments.  \xef\x82\xa7 Distributed newsletters and correspondence to constituents.    August 2009  May 2010    ACTIVITIES:  Secretary, Student Government Association  Member, Golden Key Honor Society  Member, Computer Science Society (ACM student chapter)    December 2012 Present  May 2011  Present  September 2009  Present    10    SAMPLE 6: Chronological  (Student w/internship experience - Seeking Entry-Level Position)    MARTINA SEGURA___________________________________________________________  m.segura@gmail.com | 123-345-7890  EDUCATION____________________________________________________________________  DePaul University, Chicago, IL  Expected June 2013  Bachelor of Science in Interactive Media  GPA: 3.6/4.0  EXPERIENCE___________________________________________________________________  Answers Media  Jan 2012  Sept 2012  Web/Interactive Intern   Assisted in uploading, organizing, and tagging media content such as image, text, and .pdf  files.   Analyzed and evaluated website interfaces for errors and design inconsistencies.   Edited and reformatted content on websites.  Global Initiatives  Oct 2011- Dec 2011  Web Intern   Collaborated with co-workers to assist in organizing information for the Global Initiatives website.   Used Design software such as Gliffy.com to design basic templates for GI website.  InContext Solutions  June 2011 Sept 2011  Social Media Intern   Assisted with setup and maintenance of clients social media pages, including Facebook and  LinkedIn, to help keep client image updated and increase interactivity with customers.   Organized web content and managed layout of client blog posts and newsletters, utilizing  Wordpress.  TECHNICAL SKILLS_____________________________________________________________  Microsoft Office  Photoshop  Illustrator  Flash CS5  InDesign  Gliffy  Wordpress  SPSS  myBalsalmiq  HotGloo  XHTML  HTML5  CSS/CSS3  JavaScript  ActionScript  Ruby  SQL  AWARDS______________________________________________________________________  Recipient - St Vincent DePaul Scholarship  2009-2012  ORGANIZATIONS_______________________________________________________________  Member - HerCDM (Womens Technology Organization at DePaul)  2010-2012    11    SAMPLE 7: Chronological Resume  (Transfer Student w/ relevant work experience - Seeking Entry Level Position in Field Related to Major)    Mark Anthony    manthony@hotmail.com| 123.345.7890    _________________________________________________________________________________  EDUCATION  DePaul University, Chicago, IL    Bachelor of Science in Computer Science    Expected June 2014    GPA 3.0/4.0  ________________________________________________________________________________________  TECHNICAL SKILLS  Systems:  UNIX, Windows XP / Windows 7, Linux (Ubuntu)  Databases:  SQL, Oracle, MS Access  Languages:  Visual Basic, HTML, C, C++, Java, PL/SQL, JDBC, Python, SQL  Software:  SQL Developer, Net Beans, Eclipse, MS Office, Visio, Photoshop  ________________________________________________________________________________________  WORK EXPERIENCE  Aspen Marketing, West Chicago, IL  Jan 2012 to Present    System Administrator  \xc2\xb7  \xc2\xb7  \xc2\xb7  \xc2\xb7  \xc2\xb7  \xc2\xb7  \xc2\xb7    Oversee and manage over 100 Word Press websites and manage customer support for sites and  customers.  Deploy new website plug-ins and updates via FTP. Work with Hosting Providers to add / move  websites and resolve technical issues.  Troubleshoot in house plug-ins and applications, followed by the submission of a bug report to  developers.  Track and troubleshoot website downtime as well as communicate with host providers.  Monitor website file changes for hacking.  Actively retrieve and test database backups for integrity.  Complete PHP projects using Qcodo Framework.    Community College of Baltimore County Essex ,Baltimore, MD    IT Support Technician    Aug 2010-Aug 2011    \xc2\xb7    Provided network and desktop support for students and faculty in classrooms and student  Lounges. Helped to maintain over 2,500 computers on the CCBC Essex campus.  \xc2\xb7 Troubleshot technical problems including system crashes, slow-downs and data recoveries.  \xc2\xb7 Analyzed and resolved problems, tracked and closed trouble tickets, and escalated issues if  needed.  \xc2\xb7 Configured and installed networks for the campus wireless system.  \xc2\xb7 Maintained accounts and performed general account maintenance tasks for enterprise users.  ________________________________________________________________________________________  ACTIVITIES  DePaul Computer Science Society (ACM-CSS) -Member  2012- Present  DePaul DeFrag (DePauls Fundamental Research in Academic Gaming) - Member 2012- Present  ________________________________________________________________________________________  PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS  ACM (Association of Computing Machinery)  Current Member    12    SAMPLE 8: Chronological Resume  (Graduate w/Internship Experience - Seeking Entry-Level Position Related to Major)    David Chen  dchen@gmail.com | 123.345.7890  SUMMARY  Highly motivated technical support professional seeks engaging career in network/systems engineering. Strong background in network and server support, systems analysis and related script programming. Experienced in tracking incident  and service requests in ticket management systems. Enjoy learning new skills and adapting to new challenges with professional growth.  Networking:  Languages:  Software:  Databases:  Operating Systems:    TECHNICAL SKILLS  IPv6, TCP/IP, SMTP, VPN, HTTP/HTTPS, DNS, NFS, POP3,  QMail, LANs, WANs, VPNs, Routers, Switches, Firewalls  C++, Java, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, XML, HTML, Python  Active Directory, Wireshark, Splunk, Nessus, PatchLink, Nmap,  Net Beans, MS Office, MS Visio  Oracle, MySQL, MS Access  UNIX, Linux (Ubuntu), Windows XP/ 7  EDUCATION    DePaul University, Chicago, IL  Bachelor of Science in Network Technologies  Deans List  4 quarters  \xc2\xb7  \xc2\xb7    August 2012  G.P.A. 3.6/4.0    Network Interconnection Technology Project  Summer 2012  Managed advanced network operations on Cisco enterprise-grade routers and switches  Analyzed network traffic data via console and self-customized web GUI (SNMP)    RELEVANT EXPERIENCE  IBM Corporation, Chicago, IL  Sept 2011- Present  Technical Support Specialist / Windows Server Support  \xc2\xb7 Troubleshoot server problems, execute ticket requests and manage server changes. Regularly apply Windows  Server patches.  \xc2\xb7 Provide individual support to remote clients and maintain client relationships.  \xc2\xb7 Diagnose network connectivity problems to machines and escalate issues to AT&amp;T team for troubleshooting.  \xc2\xb7 Perform building and troubleshooting NIC teaming on servers.  \xc2\xb7 Lead team on supporting server HDD encryption project.  Bank of America, Chicago, IL  June 2011- August 2011  Business Technical Analyst Intern  \xc2\xb7 Identified a prototype development tool for long term use in Treasury and Securities Technology department  resulting in reduced time and cost of application design.  \xc2\xb7 Built screen mock-ups for web simulation model on JP Morgans billing application resulting in faster re-work  of prototype GUI.  \xc2\xb7 Collaborated with different organizational departments resulting in consistency in meeting needs for the prototype project.  ADP, Chicago, IL  September 2010- November 2010  Intern EDI Analyst  \xc2\xb7 Monitored incoming and outgoing data transactions to maintain integrity of information ensuring compliance  with accepted business practices.  \xc2\xb7 Tested web application for functionality during pre-deployment of new IT system in the organization.    13    VI. Additional Career Center Resume Resources    The Career Center offers several options for getting help in creating and perfecting your  resume. Take advantage of one or more of the following services available to students and  alumni:    \xef\x81\xb6 Peer Career Advising: Peer Career Advisors have been specially trained to provide resume    assistance and basic career services to the DePaul community. Peers are available on a walk-in  basis during most business hours or via email at peercareeradvisor@depaul.edu for questions,  job search advice, resume assistance, and cover letter critiques.    \xef\x81\xb6 Online Tutorial and Resources: Visit the Career Centers website at    www.careercenter.depaul.edu to access an interactive resume tutorial, Instant Message a Peer  Career Advisor, or access this packet and other documents electronically.  \xef\x81\xb6 Career Advising: Career Advisors, who specialize in serving the needs of students and    alumni from each of DePauls colleges, are available to meet by appointment. Advising  sessions can cover a variety of topics, including selecting a major, advanced resume  development, job search strategies, interviewing skills, and other career-related concerns.    DePaul University Career Center  Contact Information  Lincoln Park Campus  2320 N Kenmore Ave, SAC 192  Chicago IL, 60614  (123)345-7890    Loop Campus  1 E. Jackson Blvd, Suite 9500  Chicago IL, 60604  (123)345-7890    Sarah Highstone  Career Specialist for CDM  For appointments, call or  123-345-7890 or use  my.cdm.depaul.edu    14"
</cv>
