<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cv>
"Curriculum Vitae  <label type="Name">Norris Dickens</label>  Associate Professor  Department of Communication Studies  University of Rhode Island  Email: yinjiao_ye@uri.edu  Phone: (123)345-7890  EDUCATION  Ph.D. in Mass Communication, College of Communication &amp; Information Sciences, the University of  Alabama, Tuscaloosa, 2006  Advisor: Jennings Bryant, Regan Chair of Broadcasting  Minor: Statistics  M. A. (2002), B. A. (1999) in Journalism, School of Journalism &amp; Mass Communication, Huazhong  University of Science &amp; Technology, China, 2002  ACADEMIC APPOINTMENT  Department of Communication Studies, University of Rhode Island  2012-present: Associate Professor, with tenure  2006-2012: Assistant Professor  RESEARCH INTERESTS  Social Media, Health Communication, Media Effects  TEACHING EXPERIENCE  COM 100 Communication Fundamentals  COM 210 Persuasion  COM 310 Topic in Communication: Content and Effects of Media Advertising  COM 310 Topics in Communication: Social Media in Health Promotion  COM 381 Research Methods in Communication  COM 382 Communication Theory  COM 502: Communication Research Methods  COM 520 Media Seminar: Health Communication  HONORS AND AWARDS  University of Rhode Island, 2006- present  2016 Third place in Open Research Competition, Chinese Association of Journalism and Communication  2014 Service Award, Chinese Communication Association  2014 Best 10 Articles of 2014 in Journalism and Communication Research  2011 Harrington School Project Grant, Harrington School of Communication &amp; Media  2009 Outstanding Paper Travel Award in Non-student Category, HINTS Data Users Conference, National  Cancer Institute  2008 Career Enhancement Grant Program award, Council for Research, URI  2006 First place in Open paper competition, Research Division, Broadcast Education Association  2002 Graduate Council Fellowship, University of Alabama  2001 Outstanding Graduate Student in Academics  Guanghua Scholarship  2000  Outstanding Graduate Student in Academics  Guanghua Scholarship  1999  Outstanding Graduate  1997  Outstanding Undergraduate Student in Academics  1996, 1997, 1998, 1999  Outstanding Undergraduate Student in Academics, Morals and Health    Ye 1    1997  Desheng Scholarship  1996, 1997, 1998, 1999  Renmin Scholarship  GRANTS  2013    Evaluator, Evaluation of House Parties: Experiential Marketing for Global Aid project. Bill and  Melinda Gates Foundation, Communications program (total award: $100,000; subcontract award:  $16,500)  2011  Principal investigator (with Kristina E. Ward), A content analysis of television medical dramas  portrayal of illness, medical treatment, patients and health professionals. Harrington School  Project grant, Harrington School of Communication and Media, URI ($4,750)  2008  Principal Investigator, A content analysis of television medical dramas portrayal of illness,  medical treatment, patients and health professionals. Career Enhancement Grant Program of the  Council for Research, University of Rhode Island ($4,421)  2003-2005  Telecommunications Needs Assessment and Comprehensive Telecommunication Plan for State of  Alabama, Appalachian Regional Development Commission, $160,000. (PI, Jennings Bryant;  worked as a research assistant)  2002-2004  Evaluation of Implementation and Impact of Alabama Science, Math, and Technology Initiative,  NASA, $216,000. (PI, Jennings Bryant; worked as a research assistant)  2003  Tuscaloosa Campaign to Prevent Teen Pregnancy Project (worked as a research assistant)  2003  Evaluation of Krackeroo Kids, Media Solutions, $2,500. (PI, Jennings Bryant; worked as a  research assistant)  PUBLICATIONS  Refereed Journal Articles  Ye, Y. (under review). Differences in nutrition intake and physical activity between users and non-users of  social media. Submitted to Journal of Health Communication.  Ye, Y., Xu, P., &amp; Zhang, M. (2016). Social media, public discourse, and civic engagement in modern  China. Telematics and Informatics: Special issue on Social media in China.  SSCI journal; impact factor 2.261 (Thomson Reuters Journal Citation Reports 2016)  Gu, L. L., Skierkowski, D., Florin, P., Friend, K., &amp; Ye, Y. (2016). Facebook, Twitter, &amp; QR Codes: An  exploratory trial examining the feasibility of social media mechanisms for sample recruitment.  Computers in Human Behavior. Published online February 23, 2016  doi:10.1016/j.chb.2016.02.006  SSCI journal; five-year impact factor: 3.724.  Wang, L., Mundorf, N., Ye, Y., Lei, W., &amp; Shimoda, K. (2015). The impact of class discussions on  attitudes of Chinese students in the US towards culture and sustainability. China Media Research,  Special Issue: Sustainability, Resilience, and Global Communication, 11, 110-115.  Ye, Y. (2014). The role of illness factors and patient satisfaction in using online health support groups.  Health Communication, 29(4), 355-363. DOI: 10.1123/34517890.2123.456789. Epub 2013 Jul 11.  SSCI journal; five-year impact factor: 1.927\xef\xbc\x9branking\xef\xbc\x9a17\xef\xbc\x8f79\xef\xbc\x88Communication\xef\xbc\x89  Zhang, M., &amp; Ye, Y. (2014). Intermittent adoption of new communication technologies: Evidence from  eastern and western. Journalism and Communication Research, 21, 78-98.  [Best 10 Articles of 2014 in Journalism and Communication Research]    Ye 2    Zhou, S., Xu, J., &amp; Ye, Y. (2013). Effect of complimentary and conflicting commentary on sports  enjoyment. International Journal of Sport Communication, 6, 173-184.  Ye, Y. (2011). Correlates of consumer trust in online health information: Findings from the Health  Information National Trends Survey. Journal of Health Communication, 16(1), 34-49.  SSCI journal, five-year impact factor: 2.949\xef\xbc\x9bRanking\xef\xbc\x9a9\xef\xbc\x8f79 (communication)  [Featured in Neurology Now (October/November 2011). University of Google: How to find  trustworthy medical information online.]  Ye, Y. (2010). A path analysis on correlates of consumer trust in online health information: Evidence from  the Health Information National Trends Survey. Journal of Health Communication, 15,  supplement 3, 200-215.  SSCI journal, five-year impact factor: 2.949\xef\xbc\x9bRanking\xef\xbc\x9a9\xef\xbc\x8f79 (communication)  Ye, Y. (2010). Beyond materialism: The role of health-related beliefs in the relationship between television  viewing and life satisfaction among college students. Mass Communication &amp; Society, 13(4), 458478.  SSCI journal; five-year impact factor: 1.542\xef\xbc\x9branking: 37\xef\xbc\x8f79 (communication)  [Featured in numerous media worldwide, including U.S.A., United Kingdom, Canada, Japan,  India, etc. An example: Watching medical dramas may be bad for your health at  http://www.foxnews.com/health/2010/10/01/watching-medical-dramas-bad-health/]  Ye, Y., &amp; Ward, K. (2010). The depiction of illness and related matters in two top-ranked primetime  network medical dramas in the United States: A content analysis. Journal of Health  Communication, 15(5), 555-570.  SSCI journal, five-year impact factor: 2.949\xef\xbc\x9bRanking\xef\xbc\x9a9\xef\xbc\x8f79 (communication)  Zhou, S., Ye, Y. &amp; Xu, J. (2009). Social and Psychological functions of media entertainment: Present  theories and future research. Communication &amp; Society, 10, 157-178.  Ye, Y., &amp; Zhou, S. (2007). Is it the content or the person? An examination of sex appeal in promos and  sexual self-schema. Journal of Promotion Management, 13, 55-73.  Zhou, S. &amp; Ye, Y. (2006). Focusing on the African-American experience. China Media Research, 2 (1),  107-112.  Shi, C., &amp; Ye, Y. (2000). The strategies for Chinese television in the age of the Internet. Journalism  Frontier, 8, 57, 49.  Ye, Y. (1998). The content and effects of radio talk shows. Chinese Broadcasting, 10, 16-17.  Books  Chen, G-M., Peng, W., Ye, Y., &amp; An, R. (2010). Communication research methods. Taiwan: Wiseman  Publishing.  Book Chapters  Ye, Y., &amp; Zhang, M. (in press). Intermittent use of social media: Facebook and Weibo use, their predictors  and social and political implications. In Xue, K. (Ed.) Social media in China. Sage Publications.  Zhou, S., Xu, J., &amp; Ye, Y. (2015). Entertainment research effects. In Wei, R., Zhou, S., &amp; Lo, V. (Eds).  Media effects and social change. Beijing: Renmin University Press.    Ye 3    Ye, Y., &amp; McGwin, K. (2013). The impact of Facebook on participation in music subcultures, in Kun  Zhang (Ed.), Journalism and Information Communication Forum (Vol. 2012) (pp.94-105).  Wuhan: Huazhong University of Science and Technology Press.  Zhou, S., Xu, J., Ye, Y., &amp; Zhou, P. (2010). Effects of culture-congruent visuals on affect, perception and  purchase intention a comparison of U.S. and Chinese viewers. In M. B. Hinner (Ed.), The  interface of business and culture. New York: Peter Lang.  Ye, Y., &amp; Zhou, S. (2008). Is it the content or the person? An examination of sex appeal in promos and  sexual self-schema, in T. Reichert (Ed.), Investigating the use of sex in media promotion and  advertising. Binghamton, NY: Haworth Press. (Reprint)  Zhou, S., Ye, Y., &amp; Xu, J. (2007). Effects of cultural congruent visuals on affect, perception and purchase  intention, in F. C. Blumberg (Ed.), When East meets West: Media research and practice in US and  China, pp. 117-129. UK: Cambridge Scholar Press.  Zhou, S., Ye, Y., &amp; Xu, J. (2007). TV and radio research, in S. Lu. &amp; J. Hong. (Eds.) Frontiers of Western  Mass Communication Research. Beijing: Peoples University Press.  Zhou, S. &amp; Ye, Y. (2006). Focusing on the African American experience. In X. Zhong &amp; S. Zhou (Eds.),  Continuity &amp; change: Perspectives on journalism &amp; mass communication education. Beijing:  Communication University of China Press, pp. 67-74. (Reprint)  Bryant, J., &amp; Ye, Y. (2005). Myths of media entertainment. In F. Krotz &amp; P. R\xc3\xb6ssler (Eds.), Myths of the  medium company: The media society and its myths (pp.205-223). Annette Maucher, Konstanz:  UVK Publishing House.  Other Publications  Zhou, S., Ye, Y., &amp; Xu, J. (2005). On the social and psychological functions of entertainment. Modern  Advertising, 10, 37-38.  Reports/White papers  Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation Grants, Communications program  Ye, Y., Shimoda, K., &amp; Latima, M. (2015). Effects of house parties on knowledge, emotion and  engagement related to Because I am A Girl campaign: Experiential marketing for global aid.  Report to the Plan International USA. Kingston, RI.  Tuscaloosa Campaign to Prevent Teen Pregnancy Project  Reber, B. H., Gower, K. K., Ye, Y., &amp; Cummins, G. (2003, October). The Tuscaloosa Campaign to  Prevent Teen Pregnancy, Inc. 2003 Public Awareness Study. Report to The Tuscaloosa Campaign  to Prevent Teen Pregnancy, Inc. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute for Communication Research. [40 pp.]  Evaluation of Implementation and Impact of Alabama Science, Math, and  Technology Initiative, NASA, $216,000, 2002-2004. (PI, Jennings Bryant)  Ye, Y., &amp; Maxwell, M. E. (2005, June). AMSTI implementation: Spring 2005 survey of UAH 1  administrators and teachers. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL:  Institute for Communication and Information Research. [25 pp.]  Ye, Y., &amp; Maxwell, M. E. (2005, June). AMSTI implementation: Spring 2005 survey of UAH 2  administrators and teachers. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL:  Institute for Communication and Information Research. [40 pp.]    Ye 4    Maxwell, M. E., &amp; Ye, Y. (2005, June). AMSTI implementation: Spring 2005 survey of UNA 1  administrators and teachers. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL:  Institute for Communication and Information Research. [37 pp.]  Maxwell, M. E., &amp; Ye, Y. (2005, June). AMSTI implementation: Spring 2005 survey of UNA 2  administrators and teachers. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL:  Institute for Communication and Information Research. [33 pp.]  Miron, D., Kwon, J., Maxwell, M., Ye, Y., Chu, A., Cummins, G., Mackay, J., &amp; Bryant, T. (2004,  September). UNA AMSTI Summer Institute 2004. Report to Alabama State Department of  Education. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute for Communication Research. [67 pp.]  Kwon, J., Maxwell, M., Miron, D., Ye, Y., Chu, A., Cummins, G., &amp; Mackay, J. (2004  September). AMSTI Summer Institute 2004 learning survey. Report to Alabama State  Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute for Communication Research. [49 pp.]  Kwon, J., Miron, D., Maxwell, M., Ye, Y., Chu, A., &amp; Cummins, G. (2004, September). UAH AMSTI  Summer Institute 2004. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa,  AL: Institute for Communication Research. [97 pp.]  Miron, D., Ye, Y., Cummins, G., Maxwell, M., Dinu, L., Davies, J., &amp; Kwon, J. (2004, January).  Evaluation of AMSTI implementation: Fall 2003 site visits: University of North Alabama.  Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute for Communication  Research. [35 pp.]  Miron, D., Maxwell, M., Ye, Y., Cummins, G., Dinu, L., Kwon, J., &amp; Davies, J. (2004, January).  Evaluation of AMSTI implementation: Fall 2003 site visits: The University of Alabama,  Huntsville: Year One. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL:  Institute for Communication Research. [33 pp.]  Miron, D., Kwon, J., Cummins, G., Maxwell, M., Dinu, L., Ye, Y., &amp; Davies, J. (2004, January).  Evaluation of AMSTI implementation: Fall 2003 site visits: The University of Alabama,  Huntsville: Year Two. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL:  Institute for Communication Research. [38 pp.]  Miron, D., Maxwell, M., Ye, Y., Chu, A., Cummins, G., &amp; Hong, Y. (2003, October). UNA first-year  AMSTI Summer Institute 2003. Report to Alabama State Department of Education. Tuscaloosa,  AL: Institute for Communication Research. [111 pp.]  Miron, D., Maxwell, M., Ye, Y., Chu, A., Hong, Y., Cook, T., Kwon, J., Chisholm, J., &amp; Cummins, G.  (2003, October). UAH second-year AMSTI Summer Institute 2003. Report to Alabama State  Department of Education. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute for Communication Research. [120 pp.]  Telecommunications Needs Assessment and Comprehensive Telecommunication Plan for State of  Alabama, Appalachian Regional Development Commission, $160,000, 2003-2005. (PI, Jennings  Bryant)  Carpenter, C., Bryant, J., Cummins, G., Davies, J., Dent, J., Dinu, L., Givens, S. B. , Hornsby, K., Butler,  N., Clifton, K., Maxwell, M., Miron, D., Cho, S.-h., Smith, B., &amp; Ye, Y. (2004, May). Full text  of focus groups on Alabama broadband network. Report to Alabama Department of Economic  and Community Affairs. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute for Communication Research. [236 pp.]  Cummins, R. G., &amp; Ye, Y. (2004, March). Public safety stakeholders focus group report: Dothan, AL.  Report to the Alabama Telecommunications Strategic Planning Project. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute  for Communication Research. [5 pp.]    Ye 5    Evaluation of Krackeroo Kids, Media Solutions, $2,500, 2003. (PI, Jennings Bryant)  Bryant, J., Cummins, G., Ye, Y., &amp; Han, S. H. (2003, November). Evaluation of the pilot episode of  Krackeroo Kids: Comparisons with Blue's Clues and Cro. Report to Media Solutions and  Krackeroos. Tuscaloosa, AL: Institute for Communication Research. [13 pp.]  Refereed Conference Proceedings  Wang, L., Mundorf, N., &amp; Ye, Y. Service culture in international exhibition management a case study.  Proceedings of the 2015 International Conference on Management Science and Management  Innovation, Guilin, China.  Zhou, S., Xu, J., &amp; Ye, Y. (2009). Effects of congruent commercials on visualizers. Proceedings of the  2009 Asian-Pacific Conference of the American Academy of Advertising, Beijing, China.  Ye, Y. (2006). The use of informational and emotional appeals in Chinese and U.S. television commercials.  Proceedings of the 2006 Conference of the American Academy of Advertising, Reno, NV.  Refereed Conference Papers  McGwin, K., &amp; Ye, Y. (2014, May). Social media and subcultures: The relation of Facebook usage to  subcultural identity. Paper presented to the 2014 annual International Communication of  Association conference.  Zhou, S., Xu, J., &amp; Ye, Y. (2012, November). Complimentary and conflicting commentary on sports  enjoyment. Paper presented to the 2012 annual conference of the National Communication  Association, Orlando, FL.  Ye, Y. (2011, August). Toward a theoretical understanding of using online health support groups:  Motivation, ability, and doctor-patient communication satisfaction. Paper presented to the 2011  annual conference of the Association of Education in Journalism and Mass Communication, St.  Louis, MO.  Zhou, S., Xu, J., &amp; Ye, Y. (2010, June). Self-construal, congruent visuals, and their effects on perception  and purchase intention. Paper presented to the Mass Communication Division at the 2010 annual  convention of the International Communication Association, Singapore.  Ye, Y. (2009, September). Antecedents of consumer trust in online health information: Findings from the  Health Information National Trends Survey. Paper presented to at the HINTS Data Users  conference\xe2\x80\x94Partners in Progress. Silver Spring, Maryland  (outstanding paper travel award; the only travel award in non-student category by the National  Cancer Institute).  Ye, Y. (2009, May) A content analysis of the portrayals of health risks in two top-ranked television medical  dramas in the U.S. Paper presented to the Mass Communication Division at the 2009 annual  conference of the International Communication Association, Chicago, IL.  Zhou, S., Ye, Y., &amp; Xu, J. (2008, May): Visuals and visualizers: Effects of culture-congruent commercials  on U.S. and Chinese viewers. Paper presented to the Visual Communication Studies Division at  the 2008 annual convention of the International Communication Association, Montreal, Canada.  Ye. Y. (2008 May). Television pharmaceutical advertising: Portrayals of health risks, health-related  perceptions, and life satisfaction. Paper presented to the Mass Communication Division at the  2008 annual convention of the International Communication Association, Montreal, Canada.    Ye 6    Zhou, S., Xu, J., Ye, Y., &amp; Zhou, P. (2007, May). Effects of culture-congruent visuals on affect, perception  and purchase intention\xe2\x80\x94A comparison of U.S. and Chinese viewers. Paper presented to the Visual  Studies Division at the 2007 annual convention of the International Communication Association,  San Francisco, CA.  Ye, Y. (2007, May). Beyond materialism: Television news coverage of health risks, health-risk perceptions,  health-related self-efficacy beliefs, and life satisfaction. Paper presented to the Mass  Communication Division at the 2007 annual convention of the International Communication  Association, San Francisco, CA.  Zhou, S., Ye, Y., &amp; Xu, J. (2006, August). Effects of culture-congruent visuals on viewers affect  perception and purchase intention. Paper presented to the Advertising Division at the annual  convention of the Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication, San  Francisco, CA.  Ye, Y. (2006, June). Health risk information, health involvement, and life satisfaction: An exploration of  the effects of portrayals of health risks in television medical dramas on college students life  satisfaction. Paper presented to the Health Communication Division at the 2006 annual conference  of the International Communication Association, Dresden, Germany.  Ye, Y., &amp; Zhou, S. (2006, June). An examination of sex appeal in promos and sexual self-schema. Paper  presented to the Mass Communication Division at the 2006 annual conference of the International  Communication Association, Dresden, Germany.  Ye, Y. (2006, April). Television viewing and life satisfaction: The effects of perceived health risks and  perceived self-efficacy in maintaining personal health on viewer's life satisfaction. Paper presented  to the Research Division at the 2006 annual conference of the Broadcast Education Association.  [first place in the Open paper competition]  Ye, Y. (2006, March). The use of informational and emotional appeals in Chinese and U.S. television  commercials. Paper presented at the 2006 annual conference of the American Academy of  Advertising, Reno, NV.  Ye, Y. (2005, September). Emotional appeals as Eastern, Western, or universal? The incorporation of  product category into a comparative study of U.S. and Chinese television ads. Paper presented to  the Advertising Division at the annual conference of the Global Fusion, Athens, OH.  Ye, Y. (2005, August). Reducing childrens media-induced fright: A meta-analysis of the effectiveness of  coping strategies. Paper presented to the Mass Communication and Society Division at the annual  convention of the Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication, San  Antonio, TX.  Ye, Y. (2005, May). A meta-analysis of age and gender differences in childrens media-induced fright.  Paper presented to the Mass Communication Division at the annual conference of the International  Communication Association, New York, NY.  MAJOR PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES  Editorial Board Member  Mass Communication and Society (2009-present), SSCI journal  Asian Journal of Communication (2013-present), SSCI journal  Journal of Mass Communication and Journalism (Fall 2011-present)  Journal Reviewer  Journal of Communication  Journal of Broadcasting and Electronic Media  Journalism and Mass Communication Quarterly    Ye 7    Journal of Health Communication  Health Communication  Asian Journal of Communication  Journal of Trust Research  Secretary/treasurer  The Chinese Communication Association (2006 August-2013 August).  The International Association for Intercultural Communication Studies (June 2009-May 2011)  PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS  International Communication Association  Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication  Chinese Communication Association  American Academy of Advertising  Broadcast Education Association    Ye 8"
</cv>
