<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cv>
"<label type="Name">Deb Hagenes</label>  Digital Media Specialist  Curriculum Vitae    Mobile:  Fax:  Email:  Website:  Skype:    +1 123 345 7890  +1 123 345 7890  greg@atlanticstudio.ca  www.gregfisher.ca  atlantic-studio    Objective:    To craft powerful and memorable lead-generating, deal-closing digital  experiences. To further position Atlantic Studio and its partnering  services as the leading high-end, niche interactive design services.    Profile:    A Canadian from Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada, Greg Fisher is an  award-winning expert in a wide range of services including brand design  / deployment, 3D rendering, interactive / web design, planning &amp;  interpretive design, integrated marketing &amp; communication campaigns,  video production, and photography. Greg is the principle consultant for  Atlantic Studio, a Halifax-based interactive design studio with a special  interest in real estate, law, travel and tourism marketing.  After graduating from McKenzie College in 2000, Greg was quickly  promoted to Production Director at Form:Media leading countless real  estate marketing projects throughout North America. For 5 years, Greg  broadened his experience in the highly competitive Dubai, UAE property  market as the Media Manager for Shaikh Holdings, a private holding  company specializing in development, marketing and sales of exclusive  properties worldwide. Recently, Greg has been appointed as Creative  Director of Geeks Chicago, and Digital Media Architect of The OGM to  masterplan, craft and shape both corporate brands, and oversee their  respective agency divisions creative digital marketing departments.    Employment History    Aug \xe2\x80\x9809 to Present    Director - Atlantic Studio  Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Oversees the coordination, planning &amp; organization of Atlantic Studio.  Ensures a consistent creative and strategic delivery of the Atlantic Studio  brand and image. Performs primary sales, PR, social media management,  search engine optimization and creative/production.    Jul 12 to Present    Digital Media Architect - The OGM  Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Spearheaded and overseen the re-brand and revised identity and design  of The OGM, is the Chief Information Architect and UI Designer for The  OGM website and social identity. Manages a team of IT professionals and  developers to construct, maintain and expand TheOGM.com. Works with  a team of SEO and SMO specialists to implement the on and off site  marketing strategy.    Sep \xe2\x80\x9813 to Present    Creative Director - Geeks Chicago  Chicago, Illinois, United States  Masterplans the core strategic wireframing and UI/UX design deliverables  for all major corporate and enterprise-level projects. Researches and  implements traditional and fringe-level technological design trends.    Apr 04 to Aug \xe2\x80\x9809    Media Manager - Shaikh Holdings  Dubai, United Arab Emirates  Responsible for both short and long term creative strategy planning of  the company, overseen a team of IT professionals, copywriters and  graphic designers; assigned projects to staff and verified company  deadlines were being met.    Jul 01 to Apr \xe2\x80\x9804    Production Director - Form:Media  Dartmouth, Nova Scotia, Canada  Managed staff and systems of production departments; overseen  information and cost management; set and ensured each facet of several  projects timelines and deadlines.    Mobile (Canada): +1 123 345 7890, Mobile (Dubai), +971 50 953 2993, Email: greg@atlanticstudio.ca, Website: www.atlanticstudio.ca    1st Quarter, 2016    Curriculum Vitae - Greg Fisher    Education:    2009  2000  1999    Skills    Languages  Software  Programming  OS    Professional Experience: Web Design:    Project Management Professional (PMP\xc2\xae) Certification  New Horizon Computer Institute, Dubai, United Arab Emirates  Digital Media Diploma  McKenzie College, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  High School Diploma  Prince Andrew High School, Dartmouth, Nova Scotia, Canada  English  Microsoft 2010 Suite (Word, Excel, Project, Powerpoint, Access), Adobe CS6 Suite  (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Flash, After Effects, Acrobat Pro,  Premiere Pro), Autodesk (AutoCAD 2009, 3Ds Max, Combustion)  HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, XML, Flash Actionscript 2, PHP  Windows 8, Windows 7, Windows XP+, Mac OSX, iOS 7    2016  Pourvoirie M\xc3\xa9catina  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Exerience-based lead-generating and reservation capturing website, targeting the  international remote adventure fishing and toursim market.  mecatina.qc.ca  2015  Universal Properties  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Fully CMS and Yardi interated real-time property availabiliity and application  portal for one of Atlantic Canadas largest landlords.  www.universalproperties.ca  2015  Expert Home  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Cutting edge sales portal for western Canadas the finest quality Park Model  Homes, Lake Homes and Custom Cottages supplier.  www.experthome.ca  2015  Walker Dunlop  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  New website for one of Halifax's oldest and most respected law firms. An easy to  use and update, WordPress managed marketing portal.  www.walkerdunlop.ca  2015  Heroic FItness Studio  - Hoffman Estates, Illinois, USA  Design concept and wireframing created for Hustons most reknown trial lawyer.  www.heroicfitnessstudio.com  2015  Peer Realty  - Hoffman Estates, Illinois, USA  Design concept for for the US midwest premier real estate crowdfunding platform.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/peerrealty.com (design only)*  2015  Burj Technology  - Dubai, UAE  Cutting edge responsive search portal concept for Dubais property market.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/burj.ae (design only)*  2015  Dan Cogdell Law  - Houston, Texas, USA  Design concept and wireframing created for Hustons most reknown trial lawyer.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/cogdell-law.com/ (design only)*  2014  The OGM  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Internationally recognized publication platform for the energy industry.  www.theogm.com  2014  Avia Russia  - Moscow, Russian Federation  Online informational and sales portal of the international suppliers of new and  re-manufactured Russian civil and military helicopters.  www.avia-russia.com  2014  Wheels On Edge  - Toronto, Ontario, Canada  A leading automotive content publishing portal designed for video and article  writing with a fully responsive mobile component.  www.wheelsonedge.com    *Archived variations of these website are  provided where there has been a  fundamental change in the original  online content or design after handover.    Mobile (Canada): +1 123 345 7890, Mobile (Dubai), +971 50 953 2993, Email: greg@atlanticstudio.ca, Website: www.atlanticstudio.ca    Curriculum Vitae - Greg Fisher    Experience:    Web Design (continued):    1st Quarter, 2016    2014  The Maritime Explorer  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  WordPress augmented and custom designed personal travel blog and photo  journal for the global adventures of Dale Dunlop, The Maritime Explorer.  www.www.themaritimeexplorer.ca  2013  Kent Fields Estates  - Kentville, Nova Scotia, Canada  Real estate listing website and company portal.  www.kentfields.ca  2013  Spring Garden Place  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Mall directory and information portal for Halifaxs boutique shopping center.  HTML5 with responsive mobile support.  www.springgardenplace.ca  2013  Tina Olivero  - Holyrood, Newfoundland, Canada  WordPress based profile for transformational and personal coach, Tina Olivero.  www.transformwithtina.com  2013  CompuSite  - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA  WordPress supported sales website for Pittsburgh's largest provider of access  flooring systems and architectural products.  www.compu-site.com  2013  TW Fitness  - St. Johns, Newfoundland, Canada  WordPress supported sales website for personal fitness instructor, Tonya Whittle.  www.twfitness.ca  2013  The Abigail Apartments  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Residential multi-unit sales and information portal .  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/theabigailapartments.ca/ (archived)*  2013  China Rose Restaurant  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Real-time online menu and ordering/takeout system website.  www.chinarose.ca  2012  Driscoll Financial  - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA  HTML/JQuery driven lead generation site for the Pennsylvania based financial  advisory consultation and advisory service.  www.driscollfinancial.com  2011  The Homestead Group  - Chicago, Illinois, USA  Property inventory listings, informational system and lead generation website for  Chicagos largest landlord.  www.thehomesteadgroup.com  2011  Great Earth Expeditions  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Online lead generation website for Nova Scotias leading provider of scenic walking  and adventure tours. Recently upgraded with responsive mobile support.  www.greatearthexpeditions.com  2011  Koiji Restolounge  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Web based profile, and menu portal for the Calgary-based Japanese lounge.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/koijilounge.com (archived)*  2011  Misha Cirkunov  - Toronto, Ontario, Canada  Profile website for the up and coming MMA star.  www.mishacirkunov.com  2010  Ticket Chest  - Annapolis Royal, NS, Canada  Live real-time ticket broker and centralized sales portal for sporting, concerts,  theater and events in cities across the United States.  www.ticketchest.com    *Archived variations of these website are  provided where there has been a  fundamental change in the original  online content or design after handover.    2010  On The Fly Aviation  - Bermuda  A visually engaging online experience to promote Bermuda's premiere aviation  tour specialists.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/ontheflyaviation.com (archived)*    Mobile (Canada): +1 123 345 7890, Mobile (Dubai), +971 50 953 2993, Email: greg@atlanticstudio.ca, Website: www.atlanticstudio.ca    Curriculum Vitae - Greg Fisher    1st Quarter, 2016    2010  Syndicate Transport  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Calgary-based trans-continental shipping and transportation company lead  generation website.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/syndicatetransport.com (archived)*  2010  Phoenix Sky Designs  - Toronto, Ontario, Canada  Online showcase of the Toronto based art company. An advanced hybrid  HTML/Flash website.  www.phoenixskydesigns.com  2010  Fitness Group Canada  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Calgary based fitness center informational and lead generation website.  www.fitnessgroupcanada.com  2010  Seen My Ad  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Web design and branding overhaul of existing online content.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/seenmyad.com (archived)*  2010  Annapolis Royal Golf Club  - Annapolis Royal, NS, Canada  Club event notification and information website.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/annapolisroyalgolf.com (archived)*  2009 Shaikh Holdings  - Dubai, UAE  Dubai-based developer website. Flash &amp; ASP integrated.  www.shaikh-holdings.com  2009 Sanctuary Falls  - Dubai, UAE  Dubai-based development informational and promotion website. Award-winning  example of a hybrid HTML/Flash website with ASP integration technology.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/sanctuaryfalls.com (archived)*  2009 Montreal Apartement  - Montreal, Quebec, Canada  Highly successfuly single-page, bilingual, lead capturing website.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/montrealappartement.com/  2009 IntraNext Consulting  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  IT solutions company based in Halifax. Client content management system.  inext.ca  2008 The Executive Towers  - Dubai, UAE  First phase portal of Dubais Business Bay development. Pioneering use of Flash,  3D and ASP.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/theexecutivetowers.com (archived)*  2008 0 to 60  - Dubai, UAE  Dubais first automated, online luxury car rental service. Flash / ASP integrated.  www.atlanticstudio.ca/archives/0to60.ae (archived)*  2007  Palm Sales  - Dubai, UAE  Sales portal for Nakheels exclusive North American agent. Number one Google  return for The Palm &amp; World Island information.  2007  Dubai Property Auctions  - Dubai, UAE  Award-winning Dubai based property auction portal. Heavy focus on Flash/ASP.  atlanticstudio.ca/archives/dubaipropertyauctions.com/ (archived)*  2003 Nancy Regan  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Career portal for the Canadian broadcast and communications icon.  nancyregan.ca    *Archived variations of these website are  provided where there has been a  fundamental change in the original  online content or design after handover.    Mobile (Canada): +1 123 345 7890, Mobile (Dubai), +971 50 953 2993, Email: greg@atlanticstudio.ca, Website: www.atlanticstudio.ca    Curriculum Vitae - Greg Fisher    Professional Experience: Branding:    1st Quarter, 2016    2015  2014  2014  2014  2013  2013  2013  2013  2013  2013  2013  2012  2012  2012  2012  2011  2011  2011  2011  2011  2011  2010  2010  2010  2010  2010  2010  2010  2009  2009  2008  2006  2005  2005  2004    Carbon Black Properties  - Dubai, UAE  Logo Design  Sterling Aviation Resources  - Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada  Logo Design  Burj Technologies LLC  - Dubai, UAE  Brand, Logo Design  Riverland Apartments  - Chicago, Illinois, USA  Brand, Logo Design  The OGM  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Brand, Logo &amp; Usage Guidelines  Hybrid Developments Logo  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Developer Logo  Kent Field Estates  - Kentville, Nova Scotia, Canada  Brand, Logo Design  TW Fitness  - St. Johns, Newfoundland, Canada  Brand, Logo Design  The Maritime Explorer  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Brand, Logo Design  Stampede Roofing Ltd.  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  Logo Design  Jumpstart Fitness  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Logo Design  The Abigail Apartments  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Brand, Logo Design Concepts  Willow Heights  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Logo Design  Driscoll Financial  - Pittsburgh, Illinois, USA  Brand, Logo Design  ETH Contracting  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Logo Design  Avia Russia  - Moscow, Russian Federation  Brand, Logo Design  Rental Homes Canada  - Montreal, Quebec, Canada  Brand, Logo Design  WCCL Contractors Ltd.  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Logo Design  Myrmidon Fight Wear  - Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada  Logo Design  PlanBandits.com  - Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada  Brand, Logo Design  GPS Tech Canada  - Mississauga, Ontario, Canada  Brand, Logo Design  Middle East Gate Exhibition LLC - Dubai, UAE  Brand, Logo Design  Annapolis Royal Golf &amp; Country Club - Annapolis Royal, NS, Canada  Logo Design  The Kimace Group  - Dubai, UAE  Logo Design  Lakeside Tree Service  - Dubai, UAE  Logo Design  The City Living  - Montreal, Quebec, Canada  Logo Design  The Emaan Network  - Dubai, UAE  Logo Design  Phoenix Sky Designs  - Scarborough, Ontario, Canada  Brand, Logo Design  Flight Simulator Engineer &amp; Technician Association - Dubai, UAE  Logo Design  NextStays Entertainment Inc.  - Dubai, UAE  Brand Logo Design  The Property Lounge  - Dubai, UAE  Brand, Logo Design  The Executive Towers  - Dubai, UAE  Development Logo  Shaikh Holdings  - Dubai, UAE  Brand, Logo &amp; Usage Guidelines  Dubai Property Auctions  - Dubai, UAE  Brand, Logo Design  Palm Sales  - Dubai, UAE  Brand, Logo Design    Mobile (Canada): +1 123 345 7890, Mobile (Dubai), +971 50 953 2993, Email: greg@atlanticstudio.ca, Website: www.atlanticstudio.ca    Curriculum Vitae - Greg Fisher    1st Quarter, 2016    Professional Experience: 3D Rendering: 2015  2014  2013  2012  2011  2009  2008  2006  2004  2002  Professional Experience: Multimedia:    2013  2012  2009  2006  2003  2003  2002  2002  2001  2001    Professional Experience: Graphic Design: 2013  2013  2012  2010  2010  2009  2009  2009  2008  2003    The Alexander  - British Columbia, Canada  Photo Realistic Commercial Highrise and Retail Level Renderings  Nelsons Landing  - British Columbia, Canada  Photo Realistic Front and Rear Develoment Exterior Renderings  The Abigail Apartments  - Bedford, Nova Scotia, Canada  Photo Realistic Exterior &amp; Interior Renderings  Joseph Howe Building  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Photo Realistic Exterior &amp; Interior Rendering  The Plaza  - Fredericton, New Brunswick, CA  3D Interior Rendering of Fitness Area and Several Living Spaces.  Sanctuary Falls  - Dubai, UAE  12 Interior Design Packages Renderings  Sanctuary Falls  - Dubai, UAE  Custom Crystal Etched Award for Cityscape Golf Tournament  Dubai Property Auctions  - Dubai, UAE  3D Logo Treatment  Atlantis Marketing  - Dubai, UAE  3D Water Home Walk-through Video  Halifax Waterfront  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  City / Harbour Model  Universal Properties  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  YHF Airport Digital Ad Placement  Spring Garden Place Mall  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  YHF Airport Digital Ad Placement  Sanctuary Falls  - Dubai, UAE  DXB Airport Kiosk Community Interactive Walk-through &amp; Voiceover  Atlantis Marketing  - Dubai, UAE  Interactive, Off-Plan, Dubai Property Locater  Mount Saint Vincent University - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Halifax Cable Channel 33 Interface  Fortune Head Ecological Reserve - Fortune Head, NL, Canada  Interpretive Multimedia Kiosk  PEI Island Architecture  - Prince Edward Island, Canada  Informational Kiosk  Bell Bay Golf Club  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Corporate ID Rom  WHW Architects  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Corporate ID Rom  Form:Media  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Corporate ID Rom  The OGM  - Calgary, Alberta, Canada  First re-branded issue cover design  Joseph Howe Building  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Building-mounted unit availability signage  Tiller Engineering  St. Johns, Newfoundland, Canada  Online digital advertisements  Maverick Communications  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Updated image treatment, brochure, presentation and website design  Middle East Gate  - Dubai, UAE  Integrated marketing &amp; communication campaign  Shaikh Holdings Dubai, UAE  Corporate branding and identity, project imaging, publication, website  design, market teaser campaign.  Sanctuary Falls  - Dubai, UAE  Award-winning integrated marketing &amp; communication campaign  Flight Simulator Engineer &amp; Technician Association - Dubai, UAE  Integrated marketing &amp; communication campaign  The Property Lounge  - Dubai, UAE  Integrated marketing &amp; communication campaign &amp; strategy  Mount Saint Vincent University - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Dept. of Education, concept &amp; design for recruitment banners    Mobile (Canada): +1 123 345 7890, Mobile (Dubai), +971 50 953 2993, Email: greg@atlanticstudio.ca, Website: www.atlanticstudio.ca    Curriculum Vitae - Greg Fisher    1st Quarter, 2016    Professional Experience: Interpretive:    2015  2014  2014  2013  2012  2012  2009  2009  2005  2005  2004  2004  2003  2003  2003  2002  2002  2002    Awards:    2014  2013  2013  2008  2008  2005  2005  2005    Nelsons Landing  - Vancouver, BC, Canada  3D birds eye view of a signature units main floor and deck area.  Lord Nelson Hotel  - Halifax, NS, Canada  3D birds eye view of extended stay suite.  Universal Properties  - Halifax, NS, Canada  Complete floor plan rendered for full 85 unit residential inventory  The Abigail Apartments  - Bedford, NS, Canada  Complete 19 unit floor plan set  Brighton House  - Charlottetown, PEI, Canada  Building amenities and services floor plan  Spring Garden Place  - Halifax, NS, Canada  Sales focused commercial &amp; retail floor plans  Sanctuary Falls  - Dubai, UAE  Custom hand-sketched treatment to 35 unique villa floor plans  Sanctuary Falls  - Dubai, UAE  Unit &amp; plot specific Villa Analysis Sheets showcasing architectural  perspective, unit positioning, plot location and description  Palm Sales  - Dubai, UAE  Palm Jumeirah signature villa &amp; garden home master layout plan  Palm Sales  - Dubai, UAE  Interactive Palm Jebel Ali water homes master plan  Shubenacadie Canal Commission - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Signage and wayfinding system  Waterfront Development Corporation Ltd. - Halifax, NS, Canada  Waterfront Greenway multi-purpose Trail &amp; Harbourwalk Signage  Bell Bay Golf Club  - Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada  Course hole-by-hole navigator &amp; illustration of fairways and greens  Island Sunset Resort  - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Wayfinding and signage concepts  Cabot Park Beach &amp; Golf Resort - Malpeque, PEI, Canada  Resort Development Plan  Silver Fox Golf Club &amp; Campground - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Conceptual Master Plan  Mount Saint Vincent University - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Dept. of Education, concept &amp; design for recruitment banners  Purdys Wharf - Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada  Wayfinding and signage concepts    Canadian Online Publishing Awards  \xe2\x80\x98Best Website Design  theogm.com  CSS Design Awards  \xe2\x80\x98Site of the Day  gregfisher.ca  CSSWinner  \xe2\x80\x98Site of the Day  gregfisher.ca  CNBC Arabian Property Awards  \xe2\x80\x98Best Property Marketing  Sanctuary Falls  CNBC Arabian Property Awards  \xe2\x80\x98Best Developer Website  shaikh-holdings.com  Bentley International Property Awards  \xe2\x80\x98Best Property Portal  dubaipropertyauctions.com  Pan Arab Web Awards  \xe2\x80\x98Commerce &amp; Trade Winner  dubaipropertyauctions.com  Canadian Web Awards  \xe2\x80\x98Excellent Rating  dubaipropertyauctions.com    *Nominated  *Nominated  *Nominated  (5 Stars)  *Nominated  (5 Stars)    Mobile (Canada): +1 123 345 7890, Mobile (Dubai), +971 50 953 2993, Email: greg@atlanticstudio.ca, Website: www.atlanticstudio.ca"
</cv>
